<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: renewal of all things | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/renewal-of-all-things/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-08T15:45:19+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Isaiah]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/09/09/isaiah/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-09T23:53:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/09/09/isaiah</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I'll never forget the angel<br />&nbsp; flying down with cleansing fire<br />fire too hot to touch.<br /><br />My lips may be clean<br />&nbsp; but still there are times<br />&nbsp; &nbsp;when the scars smoulder with the memory.<br /><br />And so on I go<br />&nbsp; your searing stamp of approval<br />&nbsp; &nbsp;the agony and the ecstasy<br />&nbsp;a reminder that   YHWH is Salvation…</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slice of Heaven]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/03/slice-of-heaven/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-03T15:38:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/03/slice-of-heaven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
No, not <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yQT0t2s1MoE">the song</a>!<br /><br />I went for a bike ride on Friday night; no reason, I just felt like upping and heading onto the road. I turned off Wellington Parade into Yarra Park, cruising past the MCG when a bridge caught my eye. The bridge takes its pedestrian passengers over the Jolimont railway lines and across into Birrarung Marr. I imagine that it's a well-known route, but I'd never been over it, so I rode towards it and decided to stop at the top to enjoy the view.<br /><br />While I was sitting there on a bench, I was treated to an amazing aural experience. There are speakers embedded in the walls of the bridge, and they were playing an intoxicating mix of folk music from all different cultures. I sat entranced at the sensory spectacle; the beautiful city lights of Melbourne in front of me, the glow of the 'G behind me, the yellow lights on the bridge giving an other-worldly light to my surroundings, and the music of different cultures blending in sweet cacophony over the rumble of the trains passing underneath. <br /><br />It occurred to me that this was a little taste of what Heaven will be like - the music, rhythm, language and expression of every tribe, nation, culture, all gathered together in joyous expression of praise to God. And while I can't wait for that day to come (and come quick, Lord Jesus!) I'm really grateful for little sneak peaks like this :)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
