<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mild rant | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/mild-rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-28T16:17:19+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sorry, I was miles away…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:54:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote>"Blinded by distractions,<br />lost in matter-less affairs…"<br />&mdash; dc Talk, "Day By Day"<br /></blockquote><br />Recently while sitting on a train, a largely unremarkable thing happened &ndash; so unremarkable it gave me pause for thought. What was this non-event? <br /><br />I got a new PB in Bejeweled Blitz. Not just any Personal Best: I cracked the half-million mark (and beat my previous best by over 150,000)! I enjoyed the quick squirt of adrenaline as it shot through my body, and then I thought: "Huh."<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s1600/1png.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear:right; float:right; margin-left:1em; margin-bottom:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="267" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s400/1png.png" /></a></div><br />For a while now I've become increasingly frustrated and annoyed at the way the Internet and smart phones have trained my attention patterns &mdash; the classic Gen-Y dance I call "The Context-Switch One-Step". Take your electronic distraction generator in one hand, drop your head slightly, place earphones in ears, and away we go, with a one-two-three, one-two-three, facebook-check, twitter-feeds, email-check, one-more-game, when's-that-tram, one-two-three&hellip;<br /><br />&hellip;sorry.<br /><br />Such constant "engagement" (from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skinner_boxes">pellet-popping</a> to <a href="http://drinking-from-the-firehose.urbanup.com/1867465">drinking from the firehose</a>) has made it very hard for my brain to either 1) switch off or 2) give undivided attention to just one thing. Sometimes this is a benefit, but mostly, it just leaves me distracted and not at rest.<br /><br />This spills out into all sorts of areas; why bother taking the time to cook a healthy meal when "fast food" slips into the cycle more easily? Or <a href="http://www.harmonicalessons.com/">learning a new skill</a>? Or making any time investment at all?<br /><br />But the place where rubber hits road for me the hardest is spending time with God &mdash; how can <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-1.html">I</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-2.html">be</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/06/voice-part-3.html">still</a> when everything in my mind screams "hurry, hurry, faster, more!" How can I spend time meditating on a chunk of connected verses, when they seem to meld into a stream of 140-character morsels right before my eyes?<br /><br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_New_World">Aldous Huxley would be horrified&hellip;</a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Arthur: I love that picture - every time I come across it it hits home with new force, and it&#39;s a both/and scenario here in the West!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Arthur</div>
<div class='content'>
Or maybe Huxley would just <a href="http://www.acceleratingfuture.com/michael/blog/images/Amusing-Ourselves-To-Death.jpg" rel="nofollow">smile knowingly</a>...<br /><br />I love your description of the one-step!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Rebecca Simon</div>
<div class='content'>
Oh wow, this totally hit home with me. I can so relate! Being a Gen-Y tech/facebook junky frustrates me no end. The days of concentrating seem to have disappeared....but I&#39;m determined to rediscover them somehow.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice, Part 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/25/voice-part-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T00:48:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/25/voice-part-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
"Be still", the Voice said.<br />What did I have to lose?<br />So I tried it and…</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice, Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/14/voice-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T22:18:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/14/voice-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
"Be still," the Voice said.<br />"Be still? Are you kidding?" I thought.<br /><br />I've got to get my<br />my views opined<br />doctrines aligned<br />vices maligned<br />sins disinclined<br /><br />My style designed<br />life plan outlined<br />hobbies defined<br />a wife to find<br />that You've assigned somewhere, presumably<br /><br />and bear in mind<br />I've got the daily grind<br />sucks out the zest, the lemon rind<br />of life that comes and perks the mind<br /><br />and all of these combined<br />just serve to take my bind<br />and wind it up<br />so this is why like most mankind<br />I'm disinclined<br />to lie inclined<br />and listen to<br />Your still, small Voice.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confused Twitter accounts: an observation]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/11/21/confused-twitter-accounts-observation/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-21T10:09:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/11/21/confused-twitter-accounts-observation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_apqCDz1JZos/SwcC3ALNPRI/AAAAAAAAAA8/o8A611fWgUU/s1600/Van+Looys.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_apqCDz1JZos/SwcC3ALNPRI/AAAAAAAAAA8/o8A611fWgUU/s320/Van+Looys.jpg" /></a><br /></div>I checked my email last evening and discovered a new batch of Twitter users had started following <a href="http://twitter.com/andrewdotnich">my account</a>. As I always do, I visited their account pages and looked for those I might be interested in following back. Unlike many Twitter users I know, I don't automatically follow every non-spam account that follows me: I look for people and organisations that I can interact with, converse with, gain value from.<br /><br />Of late, I'm seeing a lot of accounts that just seem, well, odd. I pondered this <a href="http://twitter.com/andrewdotnich/status/5888170506">out</a> <a href="http://twitter.com/andrewdotnich/status/5888190478">loud</a>, and when <a href="http://twitter.com/tdmalone">Tim Malone</a> <a href="http://twitter.com/tdmalone/status/5888274075">asked me what I meant</a>, I thought I'd try and distill my thinking into something coherent.<br /><br />There are a number of things these odd-looking accounts have in common:<br /><br /><ol><li>The accounts have a real person's name attached</li><li>The backgrounds advertise a company or an organisation</li><li>Their tweet streams don't fit either profile</li></ol><br />Let me explain what I mean:<br /><br /><ol><li>This isn't unusual at all, and by itself doesn't mean much — in fact, I expect most twitter accounts to have a real person on the other end. However, if I follow a personal account, I expect the way they tweet to reflect their personality, who they are, how they think. This is partly what makes Twitter such a rich online experience: opinions, conversations, jokes, games – there's always something going on.</li><li>I have no problem with corporate twitter accounts per sé: if you're using social media and networks to spread your company, good on you for being proactive! I follow a number of companies / organisations that I support, because they are focused and provide me with information and interaction that I wouldn't get otherwise. It provides a central point of contact for customer service, and makes hearing from these organisations easier. If I follow a company, I expect their tweets to be about services they offer, responses to customer feedback, or content that directly pertains to them.</li><li>What makes these accounts so strange to me is that they try to be both, and end up being neither. I don't expect a person tweeting as themselves to plaster advertising all over their Twitter page. On the other hand, I don't expect a company account to post quotes or links to online news stories that are of limited relevance to their organisation.<br /></li></ol><br />I am not a Social Media Expert (thank goodness!) But I do offer these suggestions under the umbrella of Common Sense:<br /><br /><strong>If you're a person:</strong> don't <em>sell</em> yourself, <em>be</em> yourself. If you're a professional, no one is going to hire/collaborate/communicate with you because of your awesome Twitter background that contains half your resume. They're going to do those things because of how you act and interact online (just as they do offline).<br /><br /><strong>If you're a company:</strong> keep your tweets directly related to company material. I don't expect a company to tell me about a news story, or give me an inspirational quote. I want to know what you're doing, and how you're making things better for your clients/customers. That doesn't mean every 2nd tweet should flog your product, but it does mean stay on message.<br /><br />Decide what type of account you're starting, and stick with that. If you want to do both, make two accounts. Trying to be both just looks weird, and ends up being neither.<br /><hr/><small>Photo: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dbullock/3567100068/">Southend: Van Looy's Sandwich Board</a> by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/people/dbullock/">DBullock</a>. Used with Permission.</small></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
A single-line anonymous insult with nothing useful to say? Ooh, insightful :)</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
&quot;I am not a Social Media Expert&quot;<br /><br />It shows.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
