<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2016-01-22T09:09:37+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kiva Snapshot]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/04/30/kiva-snapshot/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-30T19:40:50+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/04/30/kiva-snapshot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started a small group of microfinance loaners. I&rsquo;ve been building a mini site to give us a better picture of what we&rsquo;ve achieved, and what we&rsquo;d like to do next. Part of my <a href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/08/welcome-to-2015/">year of projects</a>.</p>

<h1>Build People</h1>

<p>As a well-off, young male white guy living in one of the richest countries in the world, I have <em>no idea</em> what poverty feels like. To be honest, I hope I never have to. I was raised to understand that all &ldquo;my&rdquo; money? It&rsquo;s not really mine - I&rsquo;m just a steward of it. And as someone to whom <a href="http://www.esvbible.org/Luke%2012%3A48/">much has been given</a>, I want to give a good account of what I have.</p>

<p>I believe in charitable giving - giving without expecting to receive in return. I believe that international aid is, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=inClCwsVwjY">to a point</a>, a good thing - and something that both citizens and governments alike should get behind. But not every solution fits every problem, especially at the smaller scale.</p>

<h2>Big Differences in Small Packages</h2>

<p>I really liked the concept of microfinance from the first time I heard about it. Much of the world has limited access to banking  &amp; credit infrastructure, so anything that gives these people more options is a good thing in my book. But there&rsquo;s a gap between the people looking to borrow money and those (like us) who have it. Enter sites like <a href="https://kiva.org/">Kiva</a>. Here&rsquo;s part of what they have to say about microfinance:</p>

<blockquote><p>Microfinance is the supply of loans, savings, and other basic financial services to the poor. <a href="http://cgap.org">(http://cgap.org)</a></p>

<p>As these financial services usually involve small amounts of money - small loans, small savings, etc. - the term &ldquo;microfinance&rdquo; helps to differentiate these services from those which formal banks provide.</p>

<p>Why are they small? Someone who doesn&rsquo;t have a lot of money isn&rsquo;t likely to want or be able to take out a $50,000 loan, or be able to open a savings account with an opening balance of $1,000.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you want to know more, their <a href="http://www.kiva.org/about/microfinance">introductory article on microfinance</a> is a really great place to start. Go read it now, I&rsquo;ll wait.</p>

<p>Kiva does a great job of bridging the gap between those looking to lend money and those who want to borrow it. There are plenty of micro financing groups on the ground around the world, but they often face similar problems, just at a slightly higher scale. Kiva is a clearing house that makes finding projects to fund simple. By combining loans as small as 25USD together, they&rsquo;re able to connect a large pool of lenders to a large pool of borrowers, without requiring a single lender to fund an entire loan themselves.</p>

<h2>About my group</h2>

<p>At the start of 2014, I asked around and found 9 friends willing to start a small microfinance group, using Kiva as our source of loans. I didn&rsquo;t want this group to be at the expense of other causes we were <em>already</em> supporting, so I deliberately set the bar low.</p>

<p>The rules are simple:</p>

<ol>
<li>Every month, each member contributes 5USD, so every month there is at least 50USD to loan.</li>
<li>All funds from repaid loans should be re-loaned as soon as possible.</li>
<li>Each month, one member gets to fund a loan using all the money available in our Kiva account.</li>
<li>Even though these are loans, not donations, we will not &ldquo;take the money back&rdquo;. If and when the group winds up, the funds will be donated to a charity we agree on.</li>
</ol>


<p>After just over a year in operation, the results so far have been good! In the 17 months since we started, we&rsquo;ve put in (17 x 50 = 850USD), but we&rsquo;ve loaned out 1250USD! This means that nearly half our money has been loaned twice, and this will only get faster over time.</p>

<h1>Build software</h1>

<p><aside><a href="http://github.com/anicholson/kiva_snapshot">View source code at Github</a></aside></p>

<p>Kiva <a href="http://build.kiva.org/api">has a pretty nice API</a>, which lets you pull all sorts of interesting info out about public information (loans, field partners, etc) as well as your own personal information (loans you&rsquo;ve funded, your available balance…)</p>

<p>While Kiva shows some pretty cool stats itself, I wanted to show other things, like which person funded which loan. We&rsquo;re also curious about how quickly money cycles round, so I&rsquo;ll be building some insights about that too.</p>

<h3>Screenshots</h3>

<p><img title="Graphs showing progress over time" src="http://andrewdotni.ch//images/kiva_snapshot_graph.png"></p>

<p><img title="Some of our recent loans" src="http://andrewdotni.ch//images/kiva_snapshot_loans.png"></p>

<p><img title="A tool to help me pull API data out" src="http://andrewdotni.ch//images/kiva_snapshot_api_query.png"></p>

<h3>Frontend Stack</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://angularjs.org">AngularJS</a></li>
<li><a href="http://highcharts.com/">Highcharts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bower.io">Bower</a></li>
<li><a href="http://highlightjs.org/">Highlight.JS</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bourbon.io">Bourbon</a></li>
<li><a href="http://neat.bourbon.io">Neat</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Backend Stack</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jruby.org/">JRuby 1.7.19</a></li>
<li><a href="http://sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/rails/rails/tree/4-2-stable/activerecord">ActiveRecord 4.2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://postgresql.org">Postgres 9.3</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing broken Web Fonts on Ghost]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/03/30/woff-fonts-on-ghost/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-30T16:55:58+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/03/30/woff-fonts-on-ghost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Troubleshooting Webfonts on Ghost</h1>

<p>While getting the <a href="http://blog.cogent.co/">Cogent Blog</a> up and running recently, I ran into a strange issue with the <a href="http://ghost.io/">Ghost</a> blogging platform and WebFonts - hopefully this will save you some pain.</p>

<p>We use a couple custom fonts on the blog, defining them using the CSS<wbr><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/Web/CSS/@font-face"><code>@font-face directives</code></a>. One font was worked fine, but the other consistently failed to show up.</p>

<h1>What the WOFF?</h1>

<p>For the font that didn&rsquo;t work, the browser received a 303 redirect to the same URI, but with a trailing slash. The font that worked was served just fine.</p>

<p>It turned out the &ldquo;broken&rdquo; font was in WOFF format, and the one that worked was in WOFF2 format. This wouldn&rsquo;t normally make any difference, but something was definitely odd. Our blog is hosted on <a href="http://ghost.io/">Ghost.io</a> too, so troubleshooting options were limited.</p>

<h1>Tricksy MIME Types</h1>

<p>The <s>solution</s> workaround turned out to be really simple:</p>

<blockquote><p>Rename the broken font&rsquo;s extension from <strong><code>.woff</code></strong> to <strong><code>.woff2</code></strong>, and fix the paths in the CSS.</p></blockquote>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure exactly why this works. Maybe it&rsquo;s to do with Ghost&rsquo;s routing rules – or maybe it&rsquo;s the fault of Ghost&rsquo;s CDN. Either way, hopefully this solves you some head-scratching if your fonts aren&rsquo;t working as you expect.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a MIDI Synth with a Raspberry Pi]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/02/28/midi-synth-with-raspberry-p/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-28T15:49:32+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/02/28/midi-synth-with-raspberry-p</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Background</h1>

<p>I’m a keyboard/piano player, but I’m learning <a href="http://www.marcodi.com/">the Harpejji G16</a> as well. When playing in my band, I’ve tried playing bass lines with my left hand on the keys, and leads on the harpejji with my right hand. Unfortunately, the stage piano I’ve been using is too big to sit nicely with the harpejji, and attempting V-like instrument arrangements simply gave me RSI. I needed something smaller that was really easy to use, with as little setup as switching on my current keyboard!
Part of my <a href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/08/welcome-to-2015/">year of projects</a>.</p>

<h1>What you need for this Guide</h1>

<ul>
<li>A <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/">Raspberry Pi</a>, connected to the Internet. (I’m using an original Model B)</li>
<li>A USB MIDI controller (I’m using an old <a href="http://www.behringer.com/EN/Products/UMX25.aspx">Behringer U-CONTROL UMX-25</a>)</li>
<li>An SD Card with Raspbian installed. The <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/help/noobs-setup/">NOOBS method</a> is probably easiest.</li>
<li>Speakers to plug into your Pi, for troubleshooting.</li>
<li>Option A: Monitor &amp; keyboard, for interacting with the Pi directly.</li>
<li>Option B: another PC for SSHing to your PI.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Preparing your Pi</h1>

<p>There’s a little bit of work required to get acceptable results out of your Pi. We’ll overlock this Pi, so you will need to power your Pi from a mains power supply to make sure it gets the juice it needs. From here on, we’ll assume you’ve logged into your Pi as the <code>pi</code> user and have a terminal to enter commands.</p>

<h2>Overclocking</h2>

<p>Run <code>sudo raspi-config</code>, and select Overclock from the menu.</p>

<p><img src="http://andrewdotni.ch//images/raspi-turbo.png"></p>

<p>As I won’t be using this Pi for anything else, I’ve chosen to run it at the highest overlock, Turbo. If you’re not comfortable with this, you may choose a slightly less aggressive setting. Play around and find what works best for you.</p>

<h2>Create a Separate User</h2>

<p>Depending on what you’re trying to do, this step might not be necessary. But if, like me, you want to switch the Pi on and have things “just work”, you’ll want to do this.</p>

<p>Run the following commands:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>sudo useradd -G audio synth
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This creates the <code>audio</code> group, and adds a new user called <code>synth</code> to the Pi. It also sets the synth user&rsquo;s primary group to <code>audio</code>. This is more important if you want to run your audio through the JACK audio server. I&rsquo;m choosing not to here, but it&rsquo;s an option. If you do decide to investigate JACK further, <a href="http://tedfelix.com/linux/linux-midi.html">Ted&rsquo;s Linux MIDI Guide</a> has some useful information.</p>

<p>Next, we want to allow the <code>synth</code> user to run commands with elevated privileges using <code>sudo</code>. Run <code>sudo visudo</code>, which will bring up the sudoers file.</p>

<p>Navigate to the bottom of the file, and add this line:
<code>synth ALL=(ALL) NOPASSWD: ALL</code></p>

<p>Save and exit the text editor. If no errors come up, the <code>synth</code> user should now be able to run <code>sudo</code> without needing a password.</p>

<h1>Setting up the MIDI</h1>

<p>Plug your MIDI controller into one of the Pi&rsquo;s USB ports, and make sure it&rsquo;s turned on.</p>

<p>Run <code>aconnect -o</code>, and look for your MIDI controller in the output:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>aconnect -o
</span><span class='line'>client 14: <span class="s1">&#39;Midi Through&#39;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="nb">type</span><span class="o">=</span>kernel<span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="m">0</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Midi Through Port-0&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>client 20: <span class="s1">&#39;UMX 25&#39;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="nb">type</span><span class="o">=</span>kernel<span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="m">0</span> <span class="s1">&#39;UMX 25 MIDI 1   &#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Write down your controller&rsquo;s <strong>client number</strong> - you&rsquo;ll be needing it later.</p>

<p>To verify that MIDI events are being sent, run <code>aseqdump -p *xx*</code> (replacing xx with the client number you just wrote down). Play some keys, and verify that note on/off messages are coming through.</p>

<h1>Making Some Noise</h1>

<p>There are a few options you can choose to generate sound from your Pi, but I’m going with <a href="http://fluidsynth.org/">FluidSynth</a>. CPU cycles are precious on a lower-powered device, so more complicated audio software may not work as well. YMMV.</p>

<p>Plug your speakers into the Pi&rsquo;s stereo output, and make sure they&rsquo;re switched on with the volume at a low-medium level.</p>

<p>At your Pi&rsquo;s terminal (again, assuming you&rsquo;re logged in as the <code>pi</code> user):</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>sudo apt-get update
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>sudo apt-get install fluidsynth
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Try running the aplay -L command. If the Pi complains about aplay not being found, run this too:</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>sudo apt-get install alsa
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Now run:</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>aplay /usr/share/sounds/alsa/Noise.wav
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>If everything worked properly, you should have heard noise come out of your speakers!</p>

<h1>Wiring it all together</h1>

<p>This can get a little fiddly, and I found it helpful to have 2 terminals open on the Pi at once.</p>

<p>In terminal 1, run:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>fluidsynth --audio-driver<span class="o">=</span>alsa --gain <span class="m">3</span> /usr/share/sounds/sf2/FluidR3_GM.sf2
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>FluidSynth version 1.1.5
</span><span class='line'>Copyright <span class="o">(</span>C<span class="o">)</span> 2000-2011 Peter Hanappe and others.
</span><span class='line'>Distributed under the LGPL license.
</span><span class='line'>SoundFont<span class="o">(</span>R<span class="o">)</span> is a registered trademark of E-mu Systems, Inc.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>fluid synth: warning: Requested a period size of 64, got <span class="m">256</span> instead
</span><span class='line'>Type <span class="s1">&#39;help&#39;</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="nb">help </span>topics.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>&gt;
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>In terminal 2, run:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>aconnect -o
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>client 14: <span class="s1">&#39;Midi Through&#39;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="nb">type</span><span class="o">=</span>kernel<span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="m">0</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Midi Through Port-0&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>client 20: <span class="s1">&#39;UMX 25&#39;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="nb">type</span><span class="o">=</span>kernel<span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="m">0</span> <span class="s1">&#39;UMX 25 MIDI 1   &#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>client 128: <span class="s1">&#39;FLUID Synth (1179)&#39;</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="nb">type</span><span class="o">=</span>user<span class="o">]</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="m">0</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Synth input port (1179:0)&#39;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Write down the client number for Fluidsynth as well.</p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s hook up both ends! In terminal 2, run:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="c"># xx is your midi controller, yy fluidsynth</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">$ </span>aconnect xx:0 yy:0
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Play some notes on your keyboard - you should hear some piano sounds come out of your speakers!</p>

<h1>Automating everything</h1>

<p>Doing all the setup is fine and good, but I&rsquo;m not going to lug a keyboard around and run everything each time I power on the Pi! Let&rsquo;s get it happening automatically.</p>

<blockquote><p>WARNING: Getting these next steps wrong could stop your Pi booting properly. Be careful!</p></blockquote>

<h2>Switching to upstart</h2>

<p>Run <code>sudo apt-get install upstart</code>, following the warnings carefully, then reboot your Pi.</p>

<h2>Autologin</h2>

<p>Now we&rsquo;ll set the Pi to autologin the <code>synth</code> user we made earlier. Backup <code>/etc/init/tty1.conf</code>, then edit it with sudo privileges so it looks like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'># tty1 - getty
</span><span class='line'>#
</span><span class='line'># This service maintains a getty on tty1 from the point the system is
</span><span class='line'># started until it is shut down again.
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>start on stopped rc RUNLEVEL=[2345] and (
</span><span class='line'>            not-container or
</span><span class='line'>            container CONTAINER=lxc or
</span><span class='line'>            container CONTAINER=lxc-libvirt)
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>stop on run level [!2345]
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>respawn
</span><span class='line'>exec /sbin/getty -8 -a synth 38400 tty1</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This will automatically login the <code>synth</code> user on the first terminal. You can verify this by plugging a monitor into the Pi and rebooting it &ndash; instead of seeing a login prompt you should see a shell for <code>synth</code>.</p>

<h2>.profile</h2>

<p>Whenever you log into a Linux machine, a script called <code>.profile</code> gets run. Adding our fluidsynth setup from earlier (with a few tweaks) will run everything whenever the Pi is booted up.</p>

<p>Add the following to the end of <code>/home/synth/.profile</code>:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="c"># Run fluidsynth, but this time as a non-interactive server</span>
</span><span class='line'>fluidsynth -is --audio-driver<span class="o">=</span>alsa --gain <span class="m">3</span> /usr/share/sounds/sf2/FluidR3_GM.sf2 <span class="p">&amp;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># give it time to boot up</span>
</span><span class='line'>sleep 10
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># connect the controller to fluidsynth</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Don&#39;t forget to replace these with the client numbers!</span>
</span><span class='line'>aconnect xx:0 yy:0
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># Give fluidsynth a nice high priority so it gets as much CPU as possible!</span>
</span><span class='line'>sudo renice -n -18 -u synth
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Reboot your Pi, and when it&rsquo;s finished booting, play some keys and listen to your new synth!</p>

<h1>Troubleshooting</h1>

<h2>ALSA</h2>

<p>If running <code>aplay</code> above didn&rsquo;t make any noise, perhaps you need to tweak your Pi&rsquo;s volume levels. Run <code>alsamixer</code> and check that your output is right:</p>

<p><img src="http://andrewdotni.ch//images/alsamixer.png"></p>

<p>You should make sure that the output is set to be the Broadcom chip, <em>not</em> HDMI or your MIDI device if you&rsquo;ve plugged it in. You can adjust the volume with the arrow keys &amp;endash if this isn&rsquo;t working, try pressing <code>m</code> to unmute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RubyConf AU 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/02/12/rubyconf-au-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-12T21:40:21+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/02/12/rubyconf-au-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>February 2015 saw Federation Square host the latest instalment of <a href="http://rubyconf.org.au/">RubyConf AU</a>, one of the best tech conferences in Australia. Over 450 Ruby developers from Australia, New Zealand &amp; beyond gathered for 4 days of workshops, talks, and social activities.</p>

<p><img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/rubyconf_au_15_conference.jpg' /></p>

<h1>…in 50 words or less</h1>

<p>We’re growing up, Ruby community – but it’s okay! Ruby isn’t great just because it’s new, so let’s not freak out when other New Hotnesses™ come. If we <a href="#on_the_shoulders_of_giants">learn from those who’ve come before</a>, <a href="#embrace_new_ideas">embrace new ideas</a>, and <a href="#diversity">welcome new &amp; different voices</a>, we’ll both <a href="#do_all_the_cool_things">survive and thrive</a>!</p>

<h1>…in tweets</h1>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RubyConf_AU?src=hash">#RubyConf_AU</a> may very well be my favorite conference ever. Everything was perfect, great talks, wonderful people… So good.</p>&mdash; Coraline Ada Ehmke (@CoralineAda) <a href="https://twitter.com/CoralineAda/status/563938042365239296">February 7, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rubyconf_au?src=hash">#rubyconf_au</a> thoughts: we&#39;re a creative, welcoming community. We make things.&#10;&#10;So was (is?) Perl. So is JavaScript.</p>&mdash; Michael Pearson News (@mipearson) <a href="https://twitter.com/mipearson/status/564615942324248577">February 9, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>




<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>What has been SUPER awesome about <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/RubyConf_AU?src=hash">#RubyConf_AU</a> is that despite not being a Rubyist, I got so much out of it &amp; felt so welcome. Thanks all &lt;3</p>&mdash; Liam Esler (@liamesler) <a href="https://twitter.com/liamesler/status/564033026695249920">February 7, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p><img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/collis.jpg' /></p>

<h1>…the talks!</h1>

<p>I only attended the talks, so I can’t comment on the workshops, although every attendee I spoke to enjoyed them. The 2 days of talks only had the single track, but I think they fell neatly into a few distinct categories. Here are my highlights from each :) <s>They will be available on <a href="http://eventer.com/">Eventer</a> soon, so I’ll update these with links when that happens.</s></p>

<p><strong>Update: The talks are now available, so <a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223">go and watch them all!</a></strong></p>

<h2><a name="on_the_shoulders_of_giants"></a>“Hey, there’s all this stuff people have known for a while!”</h2>

<p>As Ruby &amp; Rails get older, we’re using it to solve bigger problems (good!) and deal with <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/EldritchAbomination">Eldritchian abominations</a> created by past us (bad!).</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/loving-legacy-code-by-keith-pitty-1718">Loving Legacy Code – Keith Pitty</a></h3>

<p>Got an old, hairy codebase to look after? Keith has some gentle suggestions for getting along with it.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/a-case-for-use-cases-by-shevaun-coker-1734">A Case for Use Cases – Shevaun Coker</a></h3>

<p>or, How Neither <em>Thomas the Tank Engine</em> Nor Plus Sizes Are The Answer.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/pre-factoring-getting-it-closer-to-right-the-first-time-by-coraline-ada-ehmke-1726">Prefactoring: Getting it (Closer to) Right the First Time – Coraline Ada Ehmke</a> &amp; <a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/service-oriented-disasters-by-rachel-myers-1732">Service-Oriented Disasters – Rachel Meyers</a></h3>

<p>Two great talks on traps &amp; pitfalls to avoid when breaking apps into smaller pieces. The highlights of a strong SOA tinge through the technical talks.</p>

<h2><a name="do_all_the_cool_things"></a>“What cool things are Ruby people doing now?”</h2>

<p>Like refreshing palate cleansers on a degustation menu, these were sprinkled through at just the right times. Real cool things being done by real cool people.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/principles-of-play-by-linda-liukas-1717">Principles of Play – Linda Liukas</a></h3>

<p>This was a wonderful talk. Children are great because they haven’t learned about what they “shouldn’t do” yet. I will be <a href="http://www.helloruby.com/">buying her book</a> when I become a Dad, regardless of whether I have a son or a daughter :)</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/sweaters-as-a-service-by-amy-wibowo-1725">Sweaters as a Service – Amy Wibowo</a></h3>

<p>Amy and her team introduced Ruby to a 1980s knitting machine, and helped them to knit pretty pictures together.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/saving-the-world-literally-with-ruby-by-sean-marcia-1721">Saving the World (Literally!) with Ruby – Sean Marcia</a></h3>

<p>Big world problems don’t <em>only</em> need big solutions. Sometimes little projects can be a big help in themselves. Sean used Raspberry Pis and Ruby to give the plight of honeybees a voice.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/programming-as-performance-by-joseph-wilk-1733">Programming as Performance – Joseph Wilks</a></h3>

<p>Live coding can be just as compelling as any other live art form. Joseph gave us a peek into the tools that exist for live coding music, and then gave a stunning demo of what’s possible with Clojure + Emacs.</p>

<p><img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/repl_electric.jpg' /></p>

<h2><a name="embrace_new_ideas"></a>“What new stuff could make Ruby better?”</h2>

<p>A great mixture of humanity, high–level maths, and where our language might go in future.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/what-is-a-rubyist-by-steve-klabnik-1728">What is a Rubyist? – Steve Klabnik</a></h3>

<p>Plato, Process Philosophy, and a gentle prod to look outside our own bubble. Presented from a Moleskine, because hipster NY :)</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/consider-static-typing-by-tom-stuart-1720">Consider Static Typing – Tom Stuart</a></h3>

<p>Ruby’s dynamically typed, and attracts people who like dynamic typing. Tom wonders whether we can’t have our cake and eat it too?</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/towards-a-higher-level-language-by-erik-michaels-ober-1746">Towards a Higher-Level Language – Erik Michaels-Ober</a></h3>

<p>Ruby’s a very high-level language. But while people are trying to “make a <a href="http://www.rust-lang.org/">better</a> <a href="http://golang.org/">C</a> or <a href="http://clojure.org/">Lisp</a>”, nobody’s really trying to build a better Ruby. Why not?</p>

<h2><a name=“diversity”></a>“How can we be make ‘us’ better?”</h2>

<p>We can and should become more rounded individuals, and there are lots of paths! Trying more things, listening to others and stepping out of our comfort zones will all get us there.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/sideprojects-and-startups-by-collis-ta-eed-1723">Side Projects &amp; Startups – Collis Ta’eed</a></h3>

<p>Startups are hard. Build side projects instead. <em>Present You</em> won’t be under so much pressure, and <em>Future You</em> will have a richer set of experiences to draw on. Plus side projects don’t have to justify their existence!</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/feeling-like-a-better-developer-aka-overcoming-impostor-syndrome-by-joss-paling-1729">Feel like a better developer – Joss Paling</a></h3>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>I am not as crap as I think. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/rubyconf_au?src=hash">#rubyconf_au</a></p>&mdash; Andy Nicholson (@andrewdotnich) <a href="https://twitter.com/andrewdotnich/status/563482419630579712">February 5, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/understanding-despair-by-john-dalton-1736">Understanding Despair – John Dalton</a></h3>

<p>A great talk on depression, and how we still suck at talking about it, understanding it, and giving ourselves a break.</p>

<h3><a href="https://rubyconf.eventer.com/rubyconf-australia-2015-1223/on-second-acts-by-john-barton-1727">On Second Acts – John Barton</a></h3>

<p>or, You Can Do Post-Technical Things (and doing them will help the entire Ruby community). A call to arms for the more senior members of the community: If some of us who understand the benefits of Ruby don’t move into management, we’ll get managers who don’t and the community will suffer.</p>

<h1>Other Observations</h1>

<p><img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/picnic.jpg' /></p>

<ul>
<li><p>I loved the venue – the Edge Theatre is a stunning place and so central to everything! The only downside is that it only allowed for a single conference track. A few people were disappointed that there weren’t more “Ruby-centric” talks, and a single track probably explains most of why.</p></li>
<li><p>I liked the diversity of Social Activities. The organisers deliberately recognised that not everyone likes to go drinking at the end of every day. I thought the balance of other activities they provided catered for lots of different tastes. Well done!</p></li>
<li><p>I was pleased to meet a few <em>new</em> Rubyists at the conference. I feel like I’ve been on the fringes of the community for ages, and haven’t quite known how to “break in”, as it were. Meeting new recruits to our community gave me a chance to pay that welcome forward.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If you made it this far, well done. The conference was great, and Rubyists of any level should go next year and make it even better.</p>

<hr>


<p><aside>
Photo Credits:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/jimilaw/status/563113067676848128">https://twitter.com/jimilaw/status/563113067676848128</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/pat/status/563135596676141056">https://twitter.com/pat/status/563135596676141056</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/rubyconf_au/status/563967802239758336">https://twitter.com/rubyconf_au/status/563967802239758336</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/JonRowe/status/563532920447459328">https://twitter.com/JonRowe/status/563532920447459328</a>
</aside></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project 1, Iteration 0: Baby Sleep Monitor]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/30/baby-sleep-monitor/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-30T18:04:27+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/30/baby-sleep-monitor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this year, I <a href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/08/welcome-to-2015/">resolved to complete more projects</a>, and this is the first!</p>

<p>In just a few months time, I’m going to become a father for the first time. Being an expectant parent, and having some electronics lying around, I thought I’d combine the two!</p>

<p>The idea for this came from a <a href="http://blog.technical.io/post/100161311142/tessel-keen-io">Tessel blog post</a> - taking readings from their modules and sending them directly to a cloud data service. I didn’t want (or think I’d get away with!) bare circuit boards in my newborn’s nursery, so I decided to make a small cover for the board as well.</p>

<p>I’ll be upfront: it’s not quite finished yet. I’m annoyed about that. But in the interests of accountability &amp; transparency, iteration 0 is done!</p>

<p><img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/monitor_topless.jpg'>
<img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/monitor_with_top.jpg'></p>

<p>I made a couple of errors, which I’ll fix when I do iteration 1.</p>

<ul>
<li>I got the holes <em>almost</em> lined up correctly, but not enough to make the bolts sit smoothly with the PCB. I’ve got to be more precise.</li>
<li>I also painted the boards before drilling the holes (because I was ready to paint but not to drill) - sometimes you just have to be blocked.</li>
</ul>


<h2>What I wanted to discover</h2>

<ul>
<li>That I could simply pick up a new skill, and easily execute what I wanted to do. (This looks really embarrassing when I write it down!)</li>
</ul>


<h2>What I learned instead</h2>

<ul>
<li>I’m not as good with my hands as I thought.</li>
<li>Knowing what I want might be a good step towards the result, but it’s foolish to think I can get there in one step.</li>
<li>For me, better preparation is more important than feeling like I’m moving.</li>
<li>Iteration is totally acceptable.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kata: Bowling]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/19/kata-bowling/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-19T18:30:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/19/kata-bowling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Description</h2>

<p>Accurately model a game of ten-pin bowling. Inspired by a mini-Code Retreat I attended years ago, and the front page of <a href="http://rspec.info/">rspec.info</a>.</p>

<h2>Tests</h2>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/f0164c3948c96311cf40.js?file=bowling_spec.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>require &#39;bowling&#39;

describe Bowling do
  describe &#39;#hit&#39; do
    it { is_expected.to respond_to :hit }

    it &#39;rejects non-numeric args&#39; do
      expect { subject.hit(&#39;aha&#39;) }.to raise_exception
    end

    it &#39;rejects negative numbers&#39; do
      expect { subject.hit(-1) }.to raise_exception
    end

    it &#39;rejects higher scores than there are pins to hit&#39; do
      expect { subject.hit(11) }.to raise_exception
    end
  end

  describe &#39;#score&#39; do
    it { is_expected.to respond_to :score }
    it &#39;scores 0 for an all-gutter game&#39; do
      20.times { subject.hit 0 }

      expect(subject.score).to eq(0)
    end

    it &#39;scores the sum of pins for a game with no strikes or spares&#39; do
      attempts = (1..20).map {|_| rand(5) }
      attempts.each {|attempt| subject.hit attempt }

      puts attempts

      expect(subject.score).to eq(attempts.reduce(0, &amp;:+))

    end

    it &#39;adds the next score on when a spare is scored&#39; do
      subject.hit 6
      subject.hit 4 # spare
      subject.hit 8
      subject.hit 0

      expect(subject.score).to eq(26)
    end

    it &#39;only recognises scores on frame boundaries&#39; do
      subject.hit 6
      subject.hit 3
      subject.hit 7 # not a spare
      subject.hit 1

      expect(subject.score).to eq(17)
    end

    it &#39;adds the next two scores on when a strike is scored&#39; do
      subject.hit 10 # Strike!
      subject.hit 3
      subject.hit 6

      expect(subject.score).to eq(28)
    end

    it &#39;handles turkeys&#39; do
      3.times { subject.hit 10 }
      subject.hit 0
      subject.hit 9

      expect(subject.score).to eq(78)
    end

    it &#39;handles strikes after spares&#39; do
      subject.hit 7
      subject.hit 3  # spare
      subject.hit 10 # Strike!

      expect(subject.score).to eq(30)
    end

    it &#39;handles spares after strikes&#39; do
      subject.hit 10 # Strike!
      subject.hit 5
      subject.hit 5  # spare

      expect(subject.score).to eq(30)
    end

    it &#39;scores 270 for a 9-frame perfect&#39; do
      9.times { subject.hit 10 }
      subject.hit 0
      subject.hit 0

      expect(subject.score).to eq(240)
    end

    it &#39;scores 300 for a perfect game&#39; do
      12.times { subject.hit 10 }

      expect(subject.score).to eq(300)
    end
  end
end</code></pre></noscript></div>


<h2>Code</h2>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/f0164c3948c96311cf40.js?file=bowling.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>class Bowling
  class EmptyFrame
    def pin_total
      0
    end

    def scores
      [0,0]
    end

    def strike?; false; end
    def spare?;  false; end
    def last?;   true;  end
  end
  class Frame
    def initialize(last = false)
      @scores = []
      @last   = last
    end

    def last?
      @last
    end

    def full?
      if last?
        if (scores.first == 10) || (scores.count &gt;= 2 &amp;&amp; (scores[0] + scores[1] == 10))
          scores.count == 3
        else
          scores.count == 2
        end
      else
        strike? || spare? || (@scores.count == 2)
      end
    end

    def record(pins)
      @scores &lt;&lt; pins
    end

    def spare?
      @scores.count == 2 &amp;&amp; pin_total == 10
    end

    def strike?
      @scores.count == 1 &amp;&amp; pin_total == 10
    end

    def pin_total
      @scores.reduce(0, &amp;:+)
    end

    def scores
      @scores
    end

    def next
      @next_frame
    end

    def next=(frame)
      @next_frame = frame
    end
  end

  def initialize
    @score_history  = []
    @frames         = []
    @current_frame  = Frame.new
  end


  def hit(pins)
    raise ArgumentError unless pins.is_a? Integer
    raise ArgumentError unless pins &gt;= 0 &amp;&amp; pins &lt;= 10

    @score_history &lt;&lt; pins

    @current_frame.record(pins)

    if @current_frame.full?
      @frames &lt;&lt; @current_frame
      @current_frame.next = Frame.new(last_frame?)
      @current_frame = @current_frame.next
    end
  end

  def last_frame?
    @frames.count == 9
  end

  def score
    score = 0
    @frames.each_with_index do |frame, idx|
      next_frame           = @frames[idx + 1] || EmptyFrame.new
      the_frame_after_that = @frames[idx + 2] || EmptyFrame.new

      next_score = if frame.strike?
                     if frame.last?
                       frame.pin_total
                     else
                       if next_frame.strike?
                         20 + the_frame_after_that.scores.first
                       elsif next_frame.last?
                         10 + next_frame.scores[0] + next_frame.scores[1]
                       else
                        10 + next_frame.pin_total
                       end
                     end
                   elsif frame.spare?
                     if frame.last?
                       frame.pin_total + frame.scores.last
                     else
                       10 + next_frame.scores.first
                     end
                   else
                     frame.pin_total
                   end

      score += next_score
      puts &quot;Frame #{idx}: #{next_score} (#{score})&quot;
    end

    score
  end

  private

end</code></pre></noscript></div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Katas]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/19/katas/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-19T18:17:51+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/19/katas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Something I’ve really started to enjoy is working through software katas.</p>

<p>In karate, katas are exercises the student repeats many, many times. Each time through, the student will (hopefully) improve little by little in order to develop their technique and skill.</p>

<p>Similarly in software, katas are <a href="http://codekata.com/">small, well-defined problems</a> that are useful to practice software design techniques.</p>

<p>Inspired partly by Magnus Holm’s <a href="http://timelessrepo.com/">timeless repo</a>, I’m going to post these kata here as embedded gists, so as I update them (and make more attempts at solving them) we’ll be able to see how my thoughts on software design grow and change.</p>

<p>The first one I’m going to put up is the bowling kata, and I’ll keep the full list up-to-date on <a href="http://andrewdotni.ch/katas">the Kata page</a> :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Nov-Dec 2014: Making Soap]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/10/making-soap/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-10T16:55:01+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/10/making-soap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Why make soap?</h2>

<p>So much of what we do as software developers is intangible - you can’t taste, touch, smell or feel code! I wanted to make something that was all of those (well, maybe not taste).</p>

<p>In 2011, I took a trip to the Middle East, where I visited a soap factory in Sidon, Lebanon. The same trip I bought some soap from Aleppo, Syria, and thought it was the most wonderful soap I’d ever used. Deep green, with a thick brown patina, it felt exotic to use and wonderful on the skin.</p>

<p>I decided that I would try my hand at soap-making. I’d never done much practical chemistry, and the thought of turning something you eat into something you could wash with was fun.</p>

<h2>How does it work?</h2>

<p>At one level, soap is Chemistry 101. You mix an acid with a base, you get a neutral salt. Soap is made up of two main components:</p>

<ul>
<li>Lye (NaOH), which is a base</li>
<li>Some sort of oil, which is full of fatty acids.</li>
</ul>


<p>With the right proportions and a good stirring arm, you’ll end up with soap!</p>

<figure style='margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:100%'>
  <img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/aleppo_soap.jpg'>
  <figcaption><em>This isn&#8217;t mine.</em></figcaption>
</figure>


<h2>Did you learn anything?</h2>

<p>Apart from how to make soap, I did learn a few things.</p>

<h3>Be Prepared</h3>

<p>Like lots of activities, soap-making works best if you have everything you need before you start. You also have lots of choices: what kind of oils will you use? Will you scent it? Will you follow the “hot” process or the “cold” process?</p>

<p>Because I’d thought ahead about my answers to these questions, I was ready when a block of time became available. I had what I needed, and I didn’t need to run out and look for an ingredient because I was ready.</p>

<h3>Be Precise</h3>

<p>Soap recipes are quite precise. I actually found the precision required comforting, for two reasons:</p>

<p><strong>It helped me to concentrate on what I was doing.</strong>. Knowing too much lye or not enough stirring would ruin my batch scared me into focusing, being fully present.</p>

<p><strong>It told me what to do next.</strong> I didn’t have to make lots of decisions on the fly, and I could concentrate more on executing instead.</p>

<h3>Be Patient &amp; Persistent</h3>

<p>I knew what I wanted to do, and what I thought it would look like at the end. I still needed to do all the work required to go from ingredients to finished product. Following through and finishing gave me the real pleasure and satisfaction of a project completed. I got to use what I made, and I had pleasure in giving some away as gifts.</p>

<p>I’ll take these insights into my software projects, and my approach at work. I’m going to spell out what I need to do before I start, eliminate more distractions, and be thorough so when it’s done, it’s done.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/08/welcome-to-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-08T13:54:53+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/08/welcome-to-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone!</p>

<p>Another year has been and gone, and now 2015 extends before us as the Not Yet becomes the Has Been.</p>

<p>I have a few goals this year:</p>

<ul>
<li>Say ‘no’ to more, and finish the ‘yeses’</li>
<li>Build routine</li>
<li>Tell more stories, better.</li>
</ul>


<p>To achieve this, I’m limiting myself to the following <s>two</s>  three simple rules:</p>

<blockquote><ul>
<li>You get <strong>one project</strong> a month.</li>
<li>You <strong>have to finish</strong> that project within the month.</li>
<li><strong>Tell the story</strong> of that project, <strong>good or bad</strong>. “I just didn’t” makes a terrible story.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>Like an agile project, I’ll maintain a backlog of projects, and if I choose to prioritise them then well and good. But during the month, I’ll focus just on that project.</p>

<p>Let’s see what happens :)</p>

<h2>Projects</h2>

<ol>
<li>Baby Sleep Monitor

<ul>
<li><a href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/01/30/baby-sleep-monitor/">Iteration 0</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><a href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/02/28/midi-synth-with-raspberry-p/">Raspberry Pi-based MIDI Synthesiser</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2015/04/30/kiva-snapshot/">Kiva Snapshot</a></p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AAH14: Waleed Aly]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/12/12/aah14-waleed-aly/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-12T11:48:35+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/12/12/aah14-waleed-aly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>AAH14 Keynote - Waleed Aly: Ethics &amp; Technology</h2>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waleed_Aly">Waleed Aly</a> considered himself a strange guest speaker for a tech conference, given his background in journalism, political science &amp; law. I disagree, though - especially for a conference focusing on humanity.</p>

<p>He challenged us to think about the ethics of the space we’re working in at both micro and macro levels, and used philosophy as a backdrop for the conversation.</p>

<p>The world of philosophy is often ignored, but it provides invaluable questions of “Why?” and “Should?” that engineering, as a “How?” discipline, simply cannot.</p>

<h3>micro</h3>

<p>Q: “Are there inherent ethical challenges to the technology I’m working on?” is a question we don’t ask ourselves enough. The tech sector has a tendency to focus on what is possible first, then work out whether we should afterwards (usually after it’s too late and we’ve already done it).</p>

<p>Take (as Waleed did) driverless cars. He transposed them into the famous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trolley_problem">“Trolley Problem”</a> - where split-second decisions have moral questions. We afford ourselves a certain slack because in that situation it’s hard to know what we would choose. What about a machine, that by definition has to be told how to think? How should <em>it</em> answer the question? Even as technologists, ethics problems are <em>our</em> problems.</p>

<h3>macro, or the myth of “neutral technology”</h3>

<p>Q: Why do we tell ourselves technology is “neutral”, when it so often ends up causing changes for good and bad?</p>

<p>The introduction of the car changed forever the notion of the city. Television changed forever the notion of mass communication.</p>

<p>We tell ourselves that our technological changes (new platforms new media) are neutral - or at least that the net good will outweigh the bad. Why do we do this?</p>

<p>We talk about “the death of print” in the news industry, and assert that journalistic standards shouldn’t change. But how could we assume that standards wouldn’t change when new technology allows us to optimise speed over accuracy like never before?</p>

<p>We build drones, and drones that can wage war without people present. But what would war look like when attackers needn’t fear loss of their own life? Would they be more aggressive and kill more people? Or would they save lives by being more precise?</p>

<p>Waleed suggested that the tech industry perhaps unsurprisingly has more progressively-minded people in it than conservatively-minded. If we recognised that, perhaps we would make better-informed decisions about the social impacts our technological decisions might have.</p>

<h3>aside: Technology &amp; Worldview</h3>

<p>During Waleed’s Q&amp;A, someone asked questions as “a self-confessed ethics n00b.”. He worried the ethical conversations ended up being a waste of time because he left with more questions than answers!</p>

<p>That fascinated me, because we like to pretend we make decisions in a vacuum, or guided by “reason, science, facts, etc.” And, to an extent, we all do.</p>

<p>But we also see every fact, every piece of information through lenses, or worldviews. To deny that is the very essence of cognitive bias!</p>

<p>How could we, as people working in a quickly-changing industry, incorporate more mindfulness of our worldviews into what we do?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Above all Human 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/12/12/above-all-human-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-12T10:39:16+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/12/12/above-all-human-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past week I got the opportunity to attend the inaugural <a href="http://aboveallhuman.co/">Above All Human</a> conference, held in North Melbourne’s Arts House Meat Market. Here are some thoughts &amp; reflections I took out of it.</p>

<h2>tl;dr</h2>

<ul>
<li>There are lots of conversations we’re not having as an industry. Ethics, diversity and responsibility often end up subservient to pragmatism, profit, and monoculture.</li>
<li>“Solving a problem” is a very broad statement. Some people’s problems are finding shoes that fit; others are finding capital to finance their businesses in places with no banking infrastructure. Others just want to find cool links on the Internet.</li>
<li>Just because people are internet-famous and can start cool businesses, doesn’t guarantee that they have insight to share.</li>
<li>Listen to people who are not like yourself, and you will learn.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Highlights</h2>

<p><strong><a href="https://medium.com/@bronwen/what-are-you-going-to-do-with-your-beautiful-fragile-life-4ce679c25b40">Bronwen &amp; Susan’s opening remarks</a></strong></p>

<p><strong>Morning keynotes</strong> Perhaps I was just more awake in the morning, but I felt it was the best part. The morning keynote-ish talks were awesome, and I’ll give them some air time of their own.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23aah14">#aah14</a></strong> The conversations happening on twitter were amazing, and having MC <a href="https://twitter.com/mpesce">@mpesce</a> actively participating helped those back-channel interactions feed back into the main show.</p>

<p><strong>Diversity of speakers</strong> One of the organisers’ stated goals was to have a diverse lineup, across genders &amp; cultures. I think they did a great job of that. The only piece missing were older people. There is a wealth of wisdom in the older voices in tech that would have been great to see there.</p>

<p><strong>The venue</strong> all the tech conferences I’ve attended in Melbourne have been, sadly, a touch on the bland side. But the Meat Market was a great venue, and the mingling space outside the auditorium was a fun place to hang out, chat, and get refueled.</p>

<h2>Lowlights</h2>

<p><strong>VC panel</strong> I was really interested in the questions being asked of the VC guests - about diversity in VC funding, approaches Australian companies can take in a smaller pond of money, and why an “exit” is pretty much the only strategy VC seems to be interested in.</p>

<p>Their answers? “I’ll fund what appeals to me”, “maybe you <strong>should</strong> just go to the Valley”, and “because 1000x, duh”.</p>

<p>A sad irony that those keen to invest in “innovation”, etc. feel no need (or interest) to innovate their own practices. What would disrupting the VC space look like?</p>

<p><strong>YC Office Hours</strong> This was a strange segment - designed to mimic the YC pitching sessions, but on stage in front of an audience. It felt a bit like free advertising for YCombinator, and (even more oddly) most of the pitching companies didn’t seem that interested in their advice anyway. If I’d made any of those companies I suppose I’d be defensive of my baby too - but it made for a strange (voyeuristic?) experience.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/bronwen">Bronwen</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/sw">Susan</a> for organising a wonderful conference. We need more of these conversations in our industry. Well done &amp; see you next year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Curse of the Ideal Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/10/22/the-curse-of-the-ideal-project/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-22T12:25:34+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/10/22/the-curse-of-the-ideal-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I confess: I have an ideas problem. Not the <em>generation</em> of ideas, oh no.
My problem is what to <em>do</em> (or <em>not</em> to do) with them when they arrive.</p>

<p>Like many idealistically-bent people, I tend to like the <em>idea</em> more than the <em>implementation</em>. Why is that?</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/andrewdotnich">@andrewdotnich</a> Ideas are perfect. Implementation is chaos.</p>&mdash; Toby Hede (@tobyhede) <a href="https://twitter.com/tobyhede/status/524761857299460097">October 22, 2014</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>And it&rsquo;s true: there is a certain (almost-Platonic) beauty to the Idea. (The idea of idea? #stackoverflow)</p>

<p>You imagine the finished product, and it&rsquo;s wonderful. Oh, to have given birth to such an incredible <em>x</em>!</p>

<p>And then the tarnishing starts. The corrosive factors of<br>
<q>I don&rsquo;t have enough time!</q>, and <br>
<q>I don&rsquo;t know how to do this - maybe I&rsquo;ll fail!</q>, and <br>
<q>oh, someone&rsquo;s already made one of those!</q>, and <br>
<q>oh! I&rsquo;ve just had a great idea for a &hellip;</q></p>

<p>start etching away, and before long the sheen is gone.</p>

<p>Sometimes the tarnish takes longer to take hold than others. A lot of projects might even get started. But it&rsquo;s rare that a project actually makes it to &ldquo;finished&rdquo;,
because the inevitable disappointment when the actual fails to meet the Ideal feels too much to bear.</p>

<p>Wouldn&rsquo;t it be so much nicer, your <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/InsaneTrollLogic">troll-brain says</a>, if things just stayed as ideas? Why not give yourself the reward for coming up with the idea?</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Ko-Ko:</strong> When Your Majesty says &ldquo;Let a thing be done&rdquo;, it’s as good as done, practically it is done, because Your Majesty’s will is law. Your Majesty says &ldquo;Kill a gentleman&rdquo;, and the gentleman is to be killed, consequently that gentleman is as good as dead, practically he is dead, and if he is dead, why not say so?</p>

<p><strong>The Mikado</strong>: I see. <em>(Dramatic Pause)</em> Nothing could possibly be more&hellip;satisfactory!</p>

<p><em>The Mikado</em>, Act II.</p></blockquote>

<p>Only it isn&rsquo;t satisfactory. Eventually, you&rsquo;ll end up with a bunch of baby projects you killed at birth - because
in the moment you decided <q>Not Creating Anything</q> was better than <q>Creating Something Less than Ideal</q>. And we don&rsquo;t live in Plato&rsquo;s universe.
An idea is only a shadow without its fulfilment.</p>

<p>Who wants to live in a world of shadows?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 films]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/09/25/10-films/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-25T15:39:07+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/09/25/10-films</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are posts going around facebook asking what 10 books/films/tea blends have lasted with you over your life. Here&rsquo;s my movie list, in no real order of preference.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0352520/">The Life and Death of Peter Sellers (2004)</a></h3>

<p>Worth watching solely for the <em>incredible</em> performances of Geoffrey Rush, this is a gritty (and contracted) biopic of one of the greatest comedians of the 20th Century. I really resonated with Sellers&#8217; fear that beneath all the masks there was no essence, no Peter underneath. While this &ldquo;allowed&rdquo; him to immerse himself in characters like few others, it paints his life as tragically sad. Tough watching at times, but worth it.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0062622/">2001: A Space Odyssey (1968)</a></h3>

<p>A (very) long film, but its visuals are phenomenal given the time it was made. It deals with big themes (like the evolution of humankind), but most of the story is told in small segments. Our imagination is left to fill in the gaps, and it works very well.</p>

<p>Without that context, the psychedelia of the last 15 minutes or so will make no sense whatsoever. But if you&rsquo;re prepared to invest in the big themes, this is a stunning piece of cinema history.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0172495/">Gladiator (2000)</a></h3>

<p>Another long film, and one I like for different reasons. I really like Russell Crowe&rsquo;s portrayal of a loyal, dutiful soldier navigating a cunning, scheming world with integrity, even at his cost. Great soundtrack too.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0057012/">Dr. Strangelove (1964)</a></h3>

<h4>or, How I Learned To Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</h4>

<p>Another Kubrick film, and another (kindof) Sellers film. The comedy is black as black, and full of the futility that marked the Cold War. This film wouldn&rsquo;t be made today (because the &ldquo;baddies&rdquo; are much less centralised than the Cold War), but it does capture the gnawing feeling that one stupid renegade could bring the knife-edged balance of humanity crumbling down.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074958/">Network (1976)</a></h3>

<p>Possibly my favourite film of all time. All the main actors put in stunning performances - it won 3 of the 4 acting Oscars in 1976. In fact, it holds the record for the shortest performance that won an acting award - Beatrice Straight won with only 5 minutes of screen time! (She deserves it, btw.)</p>

<p>While Dr. Strangelove looks at the Cold War through a military lens, Network looks through another lens - the camera lens of a TV studio. The callous way that people, current affairs, politics and even terrorism can be used for monetary gain get a caustic examination, with the lingering suspicion that even the &ldquo;goodie/baddie&rdquo; categories might themselves be a fabrication.</p>

<p>Worth watching for the stellar acting performances, and the prophetic (!) foreshadowing of reality TV.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0133093/">The Matrix (1999)</a></h3>

<p>Everyone knows this one. Solid cast, good storyline, amazing special effects, and kicking soundtrack. Shame they never made any sequels&hellip;</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2032557/">The Reluctant Fundamentalist (2012)</a></h3>

<p>Found this while on honeymoon, and Verity kindly agreed to watch it. Tells the story of a young Pakistani man, who goes to chase the American Dream and support his family. But it&rsquo;s on a collision course with his homeland, and he has some decisions to make.</p>

<p>Good, because it gives a non-American, non-Western voice to the modern conflict between militant Islam, imperial America, and the people who live under their ideologies.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082158/">Chariots of Fire (1981)</a></h3>

<p>Finally a predominantly positive film! A great story about a Christian athlete who takes his faith seriously in a culture dominated by lip service. A compelling story, and there&rsquo;s <em>that</em> opening sequence.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0210945/">Remember the Titans (2000)</a></h3>

<p>America. 1970s. Race relations. Reconciliation. Killer soundtrack. Denzel Washington &amp; Donald Faison. #saynomore</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0454776/">Amazing Grace (2006)</a></h3>

<p>Biopic about William Wilberforce, and his tireless attempts to abolish the slave trade in Europe. As a Christian who cares about the world, Wilberforce is a tremendous example of determination to right an injustice. It&rsquo;s such a terrible shame that so many people around the world are still in slavery of varying kinds. Wonderful performances by Albert Finney as John Newton, and Benedict Cumberbatch (before he was Sherlock!) as Prime Minister William Pitt.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0056172/">Lawrence of Arabia (1962)</a></h3>

<p>I need to thank my brother David for inviting me to watch this.</p>

<p>Two things:</p>

<ul>
<li>This movie, more than any other in this list (perhaps with the exception of the 2 Kubrick films) needs to be watched on a <em>big</em> screen. The cinematography is stunningly good, and gives a real energy to the desert. It was also shot on sumptuous 70mm film (with its 6-channel audio), so there is an incredible richness to the imagery and sound.</li>
<li>This movie is <em>long</em>. The director&rsquo;s cut is <em>228 minutes</em>, or 3 hours and 48 minutes in duration! There is a shorter re-release, but don&rsquo;t bother. Watch it all.</li>
</ul>


<p>Despite its historical setting, and the many things one can learn about that region of the world from watching, it&rsquo;s more of a character film than anything. Lawrence gets caught up in events and, despite knowing more about the Arab world than many of his British colleagues, still manages to find himself on the wrong side of everyone, including himself.</p>

<p>Watch it. You won&rsquo;t be disappointed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Talks: August 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/20/talks-august-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-20T11:28:17+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/20/talks-august-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently been enjoying refreshing my Ruby testing &amp; design skills, and these 3 talks have been excellent. They&rsquo;re not new talks; I&rsquo;ve seen some of them before. It never hurts to be reminded about good design and good practices!</p>

<h3>The Magic Tricks of Testing</h3>

<h4>Sandi Metz</h4>

<iframe width="853" height="480" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/URSWYvyc42M?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Watch it because:</strong> the rules for unit testing minimalism are actually kind of simple - we just need to remember them!</p>

<h3>Yay! Mocks!</h3>

<h4>Corey Haines</h4>

<iframe width="853" height="480" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/t430e6M5YAo?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Watch it because:</strong> Listen to your tests! If you&rsquo;re finding pain in your tests, it&rsquo;s a compelling reason to rethink your design. Also cats.</p>

<h3>Refactoring from Good to Great</h3>

<h4>Ben Orenstein</h4>

<iframe width="853" height="480" src="//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/DC-pQPq0acs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><strong>Watch it because:</strong> <code>vim</code> ninja! The entire talk is done inside <code>vim</code>. Highly practical, and good arguments for keeping your public interfaces understandable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books I'm Reading: August 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/16/books-august-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-16T12:15:40+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/16/books-august-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently started reading more, thanks largely to borrowing a friend&rsquo;s kindle when on holidays for a month in June of this year. I&rsquo;m glad I have, because there&rsquo;s something great about getting immersed in a story - and that&rsquo;s as true of non-fiction as it is for fiction.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m reading right now:</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0767919394/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0767919394&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=moremusi-20&amp;linkId=J3W7YFX3IJMQVN7V">At Home</a></h3>

<h4>Bill Bryson</h4>

<figure style='margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:40%'>
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0767919394/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=0767919394&linkCode=as2&tag=moremusi-20&linkId=J3W7YFX3IJMQVN7V"><img border="0" src="http://ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&ASIN=0767919394&Format=_SL250_&ID=AsinImage&MarketPlace=US&ServiceVersion=20070822&WS=1&tag=moremusi-20" ></a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=moremusi-20&l=as2&o=1&a=0767919394" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;">
</figure>


<p>Bill seems to be incapable of writing short books, but I&rsquo;m thoroughly enjoying his look into the &ldquo;home&rdquo; and its history. I&rsquo;m particularly struck by how recent so many of the innovations we take for granted really are - and it gives me a little bit more gracious towards the digital natives who can&rsquo;t remember a world without iPhones.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1937077594/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1937077594&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=moremusi-20&amp;linkId=DEE5V7NTJATEO3PB">Start</a></h3>

<h4>Jon Acuff</h4>

<figure style='margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:40%'>
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1937077594/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=1937077594&linkCode=as2&tag=moremusi-20&linkId=DEE5V7NTJATEO3PB"><img border="0" src="http://ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&ASIN=1937077594&Format=_SL250_&ID=AsinImage&MarketPlace=US&ServiceVersion=20070822&WS=1&tag=moremusi-20" ></a><img src="http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=moremusi-20&l=as2&o=1&a=1937077594" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
</figure>


<p>This is a book full of home truths for Gen-Ys like me, who yearn to do work that matters but seem to have trouble working out how to get going. We&rsquo;ve rejected the Greatest Generation&rsquo;s tendency to work one job for life, and bought our Boomer parents&#8217; encouragement that we could &ldquo;be whatever we wanted&rdquo;. Couple that with internet celebrity culture giving people fame seemingly from nowhere, it&rsquo;s far too easy to get discouraged and discontented.</p>

<p>Jon writes as someone just that little bit farther down the road than you, which gives his message some weight without it being &ldquo;preachy&rdquo;. He is one of us, and he wants us all to do well. Don&rsquo;t pick it up without being prepared to do a little introspection, but I&rsquo;m finding that being honest with the questions it&rsquo;s raising really helpful.</p>

<hr />

<p>What are you reading right now?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Vision]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/01/on-vision/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-01T15:27:27+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/01/on-vision</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Fomolicious</h2>

<p>Until quite recently, I suffered a lot from <abbr title='Fear Of Missing Out'>FOMO</abbr>. Whenever I do a Meyers-Briggs type test, I always get <abbr>(E|I)NFP</abbr>. I&rsquo;m highly idealistic, and that made this a bigger deal for me than it might for some. I would look at my friends, see the cool and inspiring things they were doing with their lives, and fight the jealousy that welled up. I&rsquo;d look at professionals &amp; colleagues that I admired, and impatiently wonder why I hadn&rsquo;t had <em>my</em> big break yet. That idea for a product, that dream job, that business opportunity.That pressure to <q>make a dent in the universe</q>, as it were, was weighing very heavily on me (just ask my wife).</p>

<figure style='margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:40%'>
  <img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/porpoise.jpg'>
  <figcaption><em>This isn&#8217;t purpose.</em></figcaption>
</figure>


<p>No, it&rsquo;s an idol: depending on something less-than-ultimate for a source of ultimate meaning. That never works well in the end.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a committed Christian. The Bible reminds me that my life has value and purpose - even if nobody <strong>ever</strong> notices. When I remember this, and remember the only Person I need to please, I am set free!
<br>Free from the trap of puffing myself up too much.<br>Free from the inevitable disappointment, the ego bruise when reality fails to meet expectations. What a relief!</p>

<h2>Ambition &amp; Idealism are not my masters</h2>

<p>This doesn&rsquo;t mean I have to ditch my idealist streak, not at all. Idealism makes for a wonderful servant. But the peace that comes from knowing my worth is secure before I do anything allows me to avoid panic. I can applaud what others do without being jealous of my own place, and I can even find joy in the seemingly lowly. I am free to be useful. And when ambition isn&rsquo;t about making me appear bigger, a whole world of possibilities opens up.</p>

<p>In my next post, I&rsquo;ll talk about what this means in my working life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[untitled poem]]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2013/02/08/untitled-poem/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T15:23:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2013/02/08/untitled-poem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre>
Sometimes skies are only grey,
and nought makes it go away;
doesn't mean my failure, it's just life.

I promise to try hard in future
not to race with thread to suture
something only balm of time will heal.
</pre>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eight tentacles]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2013/02/03/octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-03T15:45:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2013/02/03/octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over a year since my last post, and so I decided (in typical geek fashion) to reboot it by switching blogging platforms. So goodbye Blogger, and hello Octopress!
Octopress is a different kind of blog system than many &ndash; there&rsquo;s no database, only flat files. You write a new post in a plain text file, run a command to create the generated page, and away you go! A little magic is required to serve it easily on the web (I&rsquo;m using a service called Heroku, for the other nerd in the audience), but that&rsquo;s it!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m thinking a bit about what I want to write about - the things that interest me, as well as what I&rsquo;m up to. As always, here&rsquo;s hoping it gets more love than the last effort :P</p>

<p>Hello 2013!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movember]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/11/11/movember/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-11T11:23:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/11/11/movember</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="float: left; margin-right: 3em; text-align: left;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4iMF1g43lJ0/TrxvCDPwtrI/AAAAAAAAAE4/ucxAZOmgo9k/s1600/mo_before.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4iMF1g43lJ0/TrxvCDPwtrI/AAAAAAAAAE4/ucxAZOmgo9k/s200/mo_before.jpg" width="150" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Before</td></tr></tbody></table><div style="text-align: justify;">Anyone who knows me well would agree that changes to the amount and style of hair on my head are few and far between. Once I get into a habit, it tends not to change for some time. And then, suddenly, I&#8217;ll decide it&#8217;s time for something different and without warning, spring it on the world.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">I may have just done that again.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: justify;">I&#8217;ve had a small <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Van_Dyke_beard">Van Dyck-style</a> beard for a few years, but I decided that I wanted to try something different. And what better time to do it than <a href="http://au.movember.com/">Movember</a>?</div></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;"><table cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="float: left; text-align: left; margin-right: 3em"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9M2jmE-JKqE/TrxvEQRMFJI/AAAAAAAAAFA/3imu9FDUyLo/s1600/mo_after.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9M2jmE-JKqE/TrxvEQRMFJI/AAAAAAAAAFA/3imu9FDUyLo/s200/mo_after.jpg" width="150" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Angry face - Day 0!</td></tr></tbody></table>Movember aims to raise support and awareness for mens&#8217; health issues, particularly depression and prostate cancer. Both of these issues aren&#8217;t seen as &#8220;manly&#8221; things to talk about, so I think the association with facial hair (seriously, how hard do you have to work to make a beard/moustache unmanly) is a good way of breaking the ice.</div><div style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: justify;">I haven&#8217;t yet decided what style I&#8217;ll end up with by November 30 - any suggestions? And if you&#8217;d like to get on board and support me, you can do so over at my <a href="http://mobro.co/andrewdotnich">&#8220;MoSpace&#8221; page</a> :D</div><br /><br /><br /></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital distractions: The Murderer]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/09/27/digital-distractions-murderer/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-27T17:45:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/09/27/digital-distractions-murderer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<p><a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/08/redeeming-some-time.html">A while back</a> I posted about my growing frustration with the constant distractions I allowed myself to deflected by. I&#8217;m still mulling over about what my response should be; I&#8217;ve taken some small steps, and I hope to share those another time.<br /></p><p>In the meantime, have a listen to this short story by sci-fi author <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Bradbury">Ray Bradbury</a>, called <em>The Murderer</em>.<br /></p><p>In it, a psychologist examines a man who&#8217;s had enough, and decided to take matters into his own hands…<br /><br /><small><a href="http://bit.ly/ruSef4" target="_blank">The Murderer [MP3] (9MB, ~15 minutes)</a> - (opens in a new window/tab)</small><br /><br /></p></div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
