<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: again | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/again/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-31T14:49:10+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sorry, I was miles away…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:54:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote>"Blinded by distractions,<br />lost in matter-less affairs…"<br />&mdash; dc Talk, "Day By Day"<br /></blockquote><br />Recently while sitting on a train, a largely unremarkable thing happened &ndash; so unremarkable it gave me pause for thought. What was this non-event? <br /><br />I got a new PB in Bejeweled Blitz. Not just any Personal Best: I cracked the half-million mark (and beat my previous best by over 150,000)! I enjoyed the quick squirt of adrenaline as it shot through my body, and then I thought: "Huh."<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s1600/1png.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear:right; float:right; margin-left:1em; margin-bottom:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="267" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s400/1png.png" /></a></div><br />For a while now I've become increasingly frustrated and annoyed at the way the Internet and smart phones have trained my attention patterns &mdash; the classic Gen-Y dance I call "The Context-Switch One-Step". Take your electronic distraction generator in one hand, drop your head slightly, place earphones in ears, and away we go, with a one-two-three, one-two-three, facebook-check, twitter-feeds, email-check, one-more-game, when's-that-tram, one-two-three&hellip;<br /><br />&hellip;sorry.<br /><br />Such constant "engagement" (from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skinner_boxes">pellet-popping</a> to <a href="http://drinking-from-the-firehose.urbanup.com/1867465">drinking from the firehose</a>) has made it very hard for my brain to either 1) switch off or 2) give undivided attention to just one thing. Sometimes this is a benefit, but mostly, it just leaves me distracted and not at rest.<br /><br />This spills out into all sorts of areas; why bother taking the time to cook a healthy meal when "fast food" slips into the cycle more easily? Or <a href="http://www.harmonicalessons.com/">learning a new skill</a>? Or making any time investment at all?<br /><br />But the place where rubber hits road for me the hardest is spending time with God &mdash; how can <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-1.html">I</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-2.html">be</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/06/voice-part-3.html">still</a> when everything in my mind screams "hurry, hurry, faster, more!" How can I spend time meditating on a chunk of connected verses, when they seem to meld into a stream of 140-character morsels right before my eyes?<br /><br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_New_World">Aldous Huxley would be horrified&hellip;</a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Arthur: I love that picture - every time I come across it it hits home with new force, and it&#39;s a both/and scenario here in the West!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Arthur</div>
<div class='content'>
Or maybe Huxley would just <a href="http://www.acceleratingfuture.com/michael/blog/images/Amusing-Ourselves-To-Death.jpg" rel="nofollow">smile knowingly</a>...<br /><br />I love your description of the one-step!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Rebecca Simon</div>
<div class='content'>
Oh wow, this totally hit home with me. I can so relate! Being a Gen-Y tech/facebook junky frustrates me no end. The days of concentrating seem to have disappeared....but I&#39;m determined to rediscover them somehow.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice, Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/14/voice-part-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T22:18:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/14/voice-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
"Be still," the Voice said.<br />"Be still? Are you kidding?" I thought.<br /><br />I've got to get my<br />my views opined<br />doctrines aligned<br />vices maligned<br />sins disinclined<br /><br />My style designed<br />life plan outlined<br />hobbies defined<br />a wife to find<br />that You've assigned somewhere, presumably<br /><br />and bear in mind<br />I've got the daily grind<br />sucks out the zest, the lemon rind<br />of life that comes and perks the mind<br /><br />and all of these combined<br />just serve to take my bind<br />and wind it up<br />so this is why like most mankind<br />I'm disinclined<br />to lie inclined<br />and listen to<br />Your still, small Voice.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customary apology for lack of posts]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/02/10/customary-apology-for-lack-of-posts/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-10T00:26:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/02/10/customary-apology-for-lack-of-posts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've not really posted for a while; I guess this isn't exactly the most exciting thing I try and do. Life is too full of interacting with people so I keep forgetting to come here and gush whatever's on my mind. But whatever. Maybe more this year. Maybe.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Stephen McDonald</div>
<div class='content'>
If I might gush, the new layout is looking good.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
