<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: world | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/world/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-04T10:13:32+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bourj Al-Barajneh: A lament]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/02/10/bourj-al-barajneh-lament/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-10T00:34:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/02/10/bourj-al-barajneh-lament</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
New year, new poem! Wrote this after coming back from a trip to the Middle East. Spent some time with people I barely knew (but now consider good friends) tooling around sightseeing and attempting to be make the world a better place. We did do some openly Christian stuff, but some of the images that stuck the most closely to me are from time we spent in a Palestinian refugee camp in Bourj Al-Barajneh, Beirut. There's a great NGO called the <a href="http://inmafoundation.org">Inma Foundation</a> we were able to volunteer with; painting, cleaning, and decorating their centre within the camp. Check them out. I could try and spend words and words and words explaining the plight of these refugees – but maybe you need to go educate yourself as well :). Too many words, not enough poetry!<br /><hr/><br /><blockquote><br />I saw a truck driving through Bourj Al-Barajneh Camp<br />  It carried a load of rubble<br />  And a set of keys to a dream<br />  that will never be realised.<br />  <br />I saw a man walking through Bourj Al-Barajneh Camp<br />  His body wasn't staying still<br />  But his soul was firmly stuck <br />  in that box of concrete, wires and despair. <br />  <br />I saw children playing in Bourj Al-Barajneh Camp<br />  They weren't running, excited,<br />  Full of joy and light because<br />  They didn't know they were allowed.<br />  <br />I saw a Son of Man in Bourj Al-Barajneh Camp<br />  He said He had plans for His children,<br />  For a hope and for a future.<br />  I'm glad Somebody does at least.<br /></blockquote></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
