<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: through the eyes of a child | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/through-the-eyes-of-a-child/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-31T13:30:52+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preaching to the choir of selves]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/16/preaching-to-choir-of-selves/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-16T10:51:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/16/preaching-to-choir-of-selves</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I talk a lotta talk but I don't<br />  walk a lotta walk,<br />I try to live to please You but I <br />  just can't shake the awk..ward..<br /><br />voice that nags and says "You know what?<br />  maybe take your eyes off you;<br />fix 'em firmly back on Jesus and<br />  remember&hellip;He <strong>loves</strong> you."<br /><br />"He loves you when the going's good, when<br />  all things come up Milhouse,<br />and just as much when things are grey,<br />  and all you feel is s&mdash;house!"<br /><br />"He knows you want to please Him<br />  so remember that you <em>do!</em><br />Now <strong>get out of your self-right funk</strong><br />  and go love others too&hellip;"</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Thanks, X19A, and welcome! I trust (despite your name) that you&#39;re not some sort of droid - but even if you were, I&#39;m touched that my scrawl can move your metal soul!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>X19A</div>
<div class='content'>
True and encouraging :&gt;</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voice, Part 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/06/22/voice-part-3/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-22T21:10:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/06/22/voice-part-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>"Trust Me with all your heart,"</i> You said.<br /><i>"Why?"</i> I thought, repulsed.<br /><br /><i>"Don't rely on your own perspective,"</i> You said —<br />but that made no sense at all.<br /><br /><i>"Wherever you go, realize I'm there, working,"</i> You said.<br /><i>"What have you ever done for me?"</i> I retorted.<br /><br /><i>"I'll tell you where to go,"</i> You said.<br />And I thought <i>"I'm sure you will!"</i><br /><hr /><br />There was silence for a few seconds, as You quizzically raised an eyebrow to say <i>"Really? Not even you believe that!"</i><br /><br /><small><i>*sigh*</i></small>You were right, as usual. <br /><br />And then You leaned over, gave me a hug, and said <i>"Come on, let's go this way…"</i><br /><hr/><br /><small>(Proverbs 3:5,6; Malachi1:2a)</small></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep turning the pages…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/05/01/keep-turning-pages/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-01T16:29:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/05/01/keep-turning-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote>When she had got to the third page [of another story] and come to the end, she said, "That is the loveliest story I've ever read or ever shall read in my whole life. Oh, I wish I could have gone on reading it for ten years. At least I'll read it over again."<br />But here part of the magic of the Book came into play. You couldn't turn back. The right-hand pages, the ones ahead, could be turned; the left-hand pages could not.<br />... "It was about a cup and a sword and a tree and a green hill, I know that much. But I can't remember, and what shall I do?"'<br /></blockquote>--C.S. Lewis, "Voyage of the Dawn Treader"</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Slice of Heaven]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/03/slice-of-heaven/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-03T15:38:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/03/slice-of-heaven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
No, not <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yQT0t2s1MoE">the song</a>!<br /><br />I went for a bike ride on Friday night; no reason, I just felt like upping and heading onto the road. I turned off Wellington Parade into Yarra Park, cruising past the MCG when a bridge caught my eye. The bridge takes its pedestrian passengers over the Jolimont railway lines and across into Birrarung Marr. I imagine that it's a well-known route, but I'd never been over it, so I rode towards it and decided to stop at the top to enjoy the view.<br /><br />While I was sitting there on a bench, I was treated to an amazing aural experience. There are speakers embedded in the walls of the bridge, and they were playing an intoxicating mix of folk music from all different cultures. I sat entranced at the sensory spectacle; the beautiful city lights of Melbourne in front of me, the glow of the 'G behind me, the yellow lights on the bridge giving an other-worldly light to my surroundings, and the music of different cultures blending in sweet cacophony over the rumble of the trains passing underneath. <br /><br />It occurred to me that this was a little taste of what Heaven will be like - the music, rhythm, language and expression of every tribe, nation, culture, all gathered together in joyous expression of praise to God. And while I can't wait for that day to come (and come quick, Lord Jesus!) I'm really grateful for little sneak peaks like this :)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
