<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: birthday | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/birthday/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-08T15:45:19+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[23]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/07/20/23/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-20T12:45:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/07/20/23</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
So today is that day, the one that distinguishes itself every year for not being an unbirthday. They seem to come around more frequently as time progresses.<br /><br />What have I learned in the past 12 months?<br /><br /><h3>I Love People (but not enough!)</h3><br />The past 12 months have brought so many amazing people into my life in such ways that I couldn't, wouldn't have believed had they not happened. 2 countries, 4 cities, 3 churches, 2 universities, countless individuals – it really blows my mind how many awesome people I didn't know just 12 months ago (well, 18 for some, but I hardly knew you guys then). I'm coming to realise that I love interacting with people more than almost anything in the world. What makes you special? What makes you tick? What are your gifts, talents, abilities? I want to know!<br /><br /><h3>I Love God (but not enough!)</h3><br />There have been times in the last 12 months when I have doubted my faith, when I have questioned whether the God I believe in is capable and trustworthy. Can He do what He promises? <br /><br />There have been so many reminders (including one just last week at Summit – thanks Pete Leslie!) that the answer is a resounding, overwhelming YES! All through the Bible there are reminders for weak people like me who have asked this question all through history. And every time, God has not let them down. <br /><br /><h3>I Love Coffee (just a little too much!) </h3><br />…which will come as a surprise to precisely no one…<br /><br /><br /><h3>Looking ahead</h3><br />The next 12 months will be an interesting ride. I've nearly finished my uni degree, and I'm not hanging around for honours, so the question of what to <strong>do</strong> will be on the agenda. (It'll be <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0024FA5IG?ie=UTF8&tag=moremusi-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=9325&creativeASIN=B0024FA5IG">something</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=moremusi-20&l=as2&o=1&a=B0024FA5IG" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />, at least) I have some ideas, including some slightly off-the-wall ones; but we'll see what pans out. Gotta actually graduate first, that's priority #1!<br /><br />I think these words of the apostle Paul will be my catch-cry for the year ahead:<br /><br /><blockquote><br />Not that I have already obtained this or am already perfect, but I press on to make it my own, because Christ Jesus has made me his own. Brothers, I do not consider that I have made it my own. But one thing I do: forgetting what lies behind and straining forward to what lies ahead, I press on toward the goal for the prize of the upward call of God in Christ Jesus. Let those of us who are mature think this way, and if in anything you think otherwise, God will reveal that also to you. Only let us hold true to what we have attained.<br /><cite>Philippians 3:12-16, ESV</cite><br /></blockquote><br /><br />Press with me, won't you?<br /><br /><object width="445" height="364"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/UCbcknyDfrs&hl=en&fs=1&color1=0x2b405b&color2=0x6b8ab6&border=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/UCbcknyDfrs&hl=en&fs=1&color1=0x2b405b&color2=0x6b8ab6&border=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="445" height="364"></embed></object></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Hey, awesome filmclip. First time I&#39;ve seen it...</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
We&#39;re gonna make it after all!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
&quot;I Love Coffee (just a little too much!)&quot;<br /><br />Telling us your name was Andrew would be more surprising.<br /><br />Now change your About Me :).</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
