<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2015-02-05T09:18:52+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Above all Human 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/12/12/above-all-human-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-12T10:39:16+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/12/12/above-all-human-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past week I got the opportunity to attend the inaugural <a href="http://aboveallhuman.co/">Above All Human</a> conference, held in North Melbourne’s Arts House Meat Market. Here are some thoughts &amp; reflections I took out of it.</p>

<h2>tl;dr</h2>

<ul>
<li>There are lots of conversations we’re not having as an industry. Ethics, diversity and responsibility often end up subservient to pragmatism, profit, and monoculture.</li>
<li>“Solving a problem” is a very broad statement. Some people’s problems are finding shoes that fit; others are finding capital to finance their businesses in places with no banking infrastructure. Others just want to find cool links on the Internet.</li>
<li>Just because people are internet-famous and can start cool businesses, doesn’t guarantee that they have insight to share.</li>
<li>Listen to people who are not like yourself, and you will learn.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Highlights</h2>

<p><strong><a href="https://medium.com/@bronwen/what-are-you-going-to-do-with-your-beautiful-fragile-life-4ce679c25b40">Bronwen &amp; Susan’s opening remarks</a></strong></p>

<p><strong>Morning keynotes</strong> Perhaps I was just more awake in the morning, but I felt it was the best part. The morning keynote-ish talks were awesome, and I’ll give them some air time of their own.</p>

<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23aah14">#aah14</a></strong> The conversations happening on twitter were amazing, and having MC <a href="https://twitter.com/mpesce">@mpesce</a> actively participating helped those back-channel interactions feed back into the main show.</p>

<p><strong>Diversity of speakers</strong> One of the organisers’ stated goals was to have a diverse lineup, across genders &amp; cultures. I think they did a great job of that. The only piece missing were older people. There is a wealth of wisdom in the older voices in tech that would have been great to see there.</p>

<p><strong>The venue</strong> all the tech conferences I’ve attended in Melbourne have been, sadly, a touch on the bland side. But the Meat Market was a great venue, and the mingling space outside the auditorium was a fun place to hang out, chat, and get refueled.</p>

<h2>Lowlights</h2>

<p><strong>VC panel</strong> I was really interested in the questions being asked of the VC guests - about diversity in VC funding, approaches Australian companies can take in a smaller pond of money, and why an “exit” is pretty much the only strategy VC seems to be interested in.</p>

<p>Their answers? “I’ll fund what appeals to me”, “maybe you <strong>should</strong> just go to the Valley”, and “because 1000x, duh”.</p>

<p>A sad irony that those keen to invest in “innovation”, etc. feel no need (or interest) to innovate their own practices. What would disrupting the VC space look like?</p>

<p><strong>YC Office Hours</strong> This was a strange segment - designed to mimic the YC pitching sessions, but on stage in front of an audience. It felt a bit like free advertising for YCombinator, and (even more oddly) most of the pitching companies didn’t seem that interested in their advice anyway. If I’d made any of those companies I suppose I’d be defensive of my baby too - but it made for a strange (voyeuristic?) experience.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/bronwen">Bronwen</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/sw">Susan</a> for organising a wonderful conference. We need more of these conversations in our industry. Well done &amp; see you next year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
