<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: training | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/training/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-03T12:56:11+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sorry, I was miles away…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:54:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote>"Blinded by distractions,<br />lost in matter-less affairs…"<br />&mdash; dc Talk, "Day By Day"<br /></blockquote><br />Recently while sitting on a train, a largely unremarkable thing happened &ndash; so unremarkable it gave me pause for thought. What was this non-event? <br /><br />I got a new PB in Bejeweled Blitz. Not just any Personal Best: I cracked the half-million mark (and beat my previous best by over 150,000)! I enjoyed the quick squirt of adrenaline as it shot through my body, and then I thought: "Huh."<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s1600/1png.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear:right; float:right; margin-left:1em; margin-bottom:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="267" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s400/1png.png" /></a></div><br />For a while now I've become increasingly frustrated and annoyed at the way the Internet and smart phones have trained my attention patterns &mdash; the classic Gen-Y dance I call "The Context-Switch One-Step". Take your electronic distraction generator in one hand, drop your head slightly, place earphones in ears, and away we go, with a one-two-three, one-two-three, facebook-check, twitter-feeds, email-check, one-more-game, when's-that-tram, one-two-three&hellip;<br /><br />&hellip;sorry.<br /><br />Such constant "engagement" (from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skinner_boxes">pellet-popping</a> to <a href="http://drinking-from-the-firehose.urbanup.com/1867465">drinking from the firehose</a>) has made it very hard for my brain to either 1) switch off or 2) give undivided attention to just one thing. Sometimes this is a benefit, but mostly, it just leaves me distracted and not at rest.<br /><br />This spills out into all sorts of areas; why bother taking the time to cook a healthy meal when "fast food" slips into the cycle more easily? Or <a href="http://www.harmonicalessons.com/">learning a new skill</a>? Or making any time investment at all?<br /><br />But the place where rubber hits road for me the hardest is spending time with God &mdash; how can <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-1.html">I</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-2.html">be</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/06/voice-part-3.html">still</a> when everything in my mind screams "hurry, hurry, faster, more!" How can I spend time meditating on a chunk of connected verses, when they seem to meld into a stream of 140-character morsels right before my eyes?<br /><br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_New_World">Aldous Huxley would be horrified&hellip;</a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Arthur: I love that picture - every time I come across it it hits home with new force, and it&#39;s a both/and scenario here in the West!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Arthur</div>
<div class='content'>
Or maybe Huxley would just <a href="http://www.acceleratingfuture.com/michael/blog/images/Amusing-Ourselves-To-Death.jpg" rel="nofollow">smile knowingly</a>...<br /><br />I love your description of the one-step!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Rebecca Simon</div>
<div class='content'>
Oh wow, this totally hit home with me. I can so relate! Being a Gen-Y tech/facebook junky frustrates me no end. The days of concentrating seem to have disappeared....but I&#39;m determined to rediscover them somehow.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sin & its aftermath]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/07/sin-its-aftermath/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-07T10:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/04/07/sin-its-aftermath</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I love it when one stumbles across a gem. I found the Tenth Leper blog through a friend because of the recent Rob Bell unpleasantness, but I've kept him in my feeds now that his reviews are done because I really like the stuff he has to say. Take this from <a href="http://thetenthleper.com/2011/04/06/the-importance-of-christian-identity-in-the-fight-against-sin/">today's post</a>:<br /><br /><blockquote>I think some of Satan’s biggest victories against us are not in his getting us to commit a particular sin, but in increasing our guilt over it.  It’s like that old proverb: “Give a man a fish and you feed him for a day.  Teach a man to fish and you feed him for a lifetime.”  Similarly, get a man to sin and you’ll separate him from God for a moment.  But get a man to feel guilty, and you’ll separate him from God forever.  Guilt causes us to believe that God doesn’t want us, that his arms aren’t open to us, that his attention can’t be grabbed except by maybe extreme effort.  It causes us to believe that we’re damaged goods and that God couldn’t possibly still want us.<br /><p>I don’t think it’s too bold to say that the moments after sin can be more dangerous than the moments before it.  How you respond to sin is so important.  Will you move further away from your only source of life and help as a result of it?  Or will you move closer to him?  We need to preach the Gospel to ourselves every day because we sin every day, and the more we sin, the more we’re reminded that on our own we have absolutely no right to speak with God.  But we need to let that drive us to Jesus as our only right to be in the presence of God.  Jesus killed sin’s guilt.  And because there’s no longer any guilt or condemnation for God’s children, then sin’s power begins to diminish in their lives, because they’re confidently running to their Father for strength.<br /></blockquote><br />Where do you run?</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This weekend…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/03/26/this-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-26T15:38:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/03/26/this-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
…I will be back in Adelaide for the first time since I left there at the end of 2008. I'll be there for the Equip Conference, a Christian training event run by the <a href="http://efac.org.au/">Evangelical Fellowship of Anglican Churches</a>.<br /><br />I'm a little apprehensive about going back, as coming back to Melbourne from overseas made me feel almost as if I'd never left (being so busy didn't hurt, either, of course :) I don't know why this suddenly comes at me; it happened just before I left Adelaide to come back to Melbourne after Christmas.<br /><br />Whatever the case, it's bound to be a valuable weekend of sound teaching and great training, and a chance to see some old new friends for the first time in a while :)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
