<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meta | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/meta/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-10-22T14:59:16+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prodigal brothers in arms]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/06/06/prodigal-brothers-in-arms/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-06T23:26:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/06/06/prodigal-brothers-in-arms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
"Are we so different?"<br />younger brother calls to elder.<br />"We both know the old dodderer<br />means well, but you've got to<br />admit He's a bit misguided.<br />We've got brains, we've got time -<br />let's go, see what <i>we</i> can do!"<br /><br />"Are you kidding?!"<br />rejoined the elder.<br />"We have a real base here! It's true<br />the Old Man is a bit tiresome, but <br />this farm's a solid investment!<br />Soon He'll die, and we can run things<br />the way they <i>should</i> be done! Or at least<br />not pretend so much&hellip;"<br /><br />So the younger ran out one way<br />and threw away his lot, while<br />the other toiled and strained and<br />worked long years on <br />his share of the plot.<br /><br />And all the while the Father grieved<br />for the day His two lost sons would<br />come back to His heart, and Home.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[like a child…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/05/17/like-child/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-17T23:06:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/05/17/like-child</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
"Don't worry, Dad, I'm a big kid now!" exclaimed the lad, straining under the weight of a big box of this-and-that. His Father smiled knowingly to Himself. The more he changed, the more he seemed to stay the same. "But he is growing," He said to himself. "And becoming more like his Brother every day."<br />And then there was a crash and a cry from down the hall, and the Father rushed to clean up the newly-created mess of boy and <i>bric-à-brac</i>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep turning the pages…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/05/01/keep-turning-pages/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-01T16:29:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/05/01/keep-turning-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote>When she had got to the third page [of another story] and come to the end, she said, "That is the loveliest story I've ever read or ever shall read in my whole life. Oh, I wish I could have gone on reading it for ten years. At least I'll read it over again."<br />But here part of the magic of the Book came into play. You couldn't turn back. The right-hand pages, the ones ahead, could be turned; the left-hand pages could not.<br />... "It was about a cup and a sword and a tree and a green hill, I know that much. But I can't remember, and what shall I do?"'<br /></blockquote>--C.S. Lewis, "Voyage of the Dawn Treader"</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New blog!]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/12/24/new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-24T14:27:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/12/24/new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
In contrast to life, there hasn't been much happening here of late. Sorry!<br /><br />However, I have just started a blog relating to the Research Project I've started at Swinburne.<br /><br />You can read about what I'm doing over at <a href="http://thegloofactory.blogspot.com">The GLoo Factory</a>. It assumes a fair amount of programming knowledge, so apologies if it doesn't make any sense :)<br /><br />A.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Sounds fascinating. You&#39;re very good at explaining things; even I enjoyed reading :D</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time for Blogging]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/14/time-for-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-14T23:35:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/14/time-for-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div style="text-align: justify;"><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/178/446501329_95e324629b_m.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer; width: 160px; height: 240px;" src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/178/446501329_95e324629b_m.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a>I really don't know how some people find the time to write decent-sized, quality blog posts on a regular basis. I have plenty of ideas and think "ooh, that would make a great blog post"; more often than not, however, they either end up in a drafts folder never to be seen again, or they are soon forgotten about.<br /></div><br />How <strong>do</strong> they do it?<br /><br /><hr /><br /><span style="font-size:85%;">Photo: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cattoo/446501329/" alt="Link to photo">cattoo on flickr</a>.</span></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Stephen McDonald</div>
<div class='content'>
Great advise Arthur.<br /><br />One blog I quite like is i.g.spong.com written by a mate (and former announcer) of mine. He also uses his blog for 1 minute radio spots, so he usually limits them to 140 words. It helps to keep them pithy.<br /><br />I've tried to restrain myself to a definite theme or topic and within that take a subject and relate it to something that's happened recently (in the news or to me personally). This usually means ignoring large areas of personal interest (e.g. media and politics), but can still allow me to deal with the issues behind them.<br /><br />*Ramble Ends*<br /><br />(I'd be up for tag teaming).</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>arthurandtamie</div>
<div class='content'>
It took me a while to get going. If you are writing for a readership, it does have to be very regular. A few things seem to help:<br /><br />- Tag-teaming with someone<br /><br />- Building up a backlog of drafts and ideas (even if they don't get published, it all goes into the mill)<br /><br />- Blogging around central topics/themes rather than random personal junk from my head<br /><br />- Stuff that other people are keen to hear about<br /><br />See http://www.problogger.net/archives/2007/07/19/the-4-pillars-of-writing-exceptional-blogs/<br /><br />Arthur</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
