<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: why | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/why/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2016-10-18T16:57:41+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Vision]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/01/on-vision/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-01T15:27:27+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/08/01/on-vision</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Fomolicious</h2>

<p>Until quite recently, I suffered a lot from <abbr title='Fear Of Missing Out'>FOMO</abbr>. Whenever I do a Meyers-Briggs type test, I always get <abbr>(E|I)NFP</abbr>. I&rsquo;m highly idealistic, and that made this a bigger deal for me than it might for some. I would look at my friends, see the cool and inspiring things they were doing with their lives, and fight the jealousy that welled up. I&rsquo;d look at professionals &amp; colleagues that I admired, and impatiently wonder why I hadn&rsquo;t had <em>my</em> big break yet. That idea for a product, that dream job, that business opportunity.That pressure to <q>make a dent in the universe</q>, as it were, was weighing very heavily on me (just ask my wife).</p>

<p><figure style='margin-left:auto; margin-right:auto; width:40%'>
  <img src='http://andrewdotni.ch//images/porpoise.jpg'>
  <figcaption><em>This isn&rsquo;t purpose.</em></figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>No, it&rsquo;s an idol: depending on something less-than-ultimate for a source of ultimate meaning. That never works well in the end.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a committed Christian. The Bible reminds me that my life has value and purpose - even if nobody <strong>ever</strong> notices. When I remember this, and remember the only Person I need to please, I am set free!
<br>Free from the trap of puffing myself up too much.<br>Free from the inevitable disappointment, the ego bruise when reality fails to meet expectations. What a relief!</p>

<h2>Ambition &amp; Idealism are not my masters</h2>

<p>This doesn&rsquo;t mean I have to ditch my idealist streak, not at all. Idealism makes for a wonderful servant. But the peace that comes from knowing my worth is secure before I do anything allows me to avoid panic. I can applaud what others do without being jealous of my own place, and I can even find joy in the seemingly lowly. I am free to be useful. And when ambition isn&rsquo;t about making me appear bigger, a whole world of possibilities opens up.</p>

<p>In my next post, I&rsquo;ll talk about what this means in my working life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
