<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: coffee | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/coffee/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-25T14:32:58+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Made it!]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/19/made-it/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-19T09:15:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/19/made-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1285/534058328_356d0cc37d.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer; width: 225px; height: 300px;" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1285/534058328_356d0cc37d.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a>The week is up, the period of mourning is over. My latest "week without caffeine" push has finally finished.<br /><br />As has proven to be the case most times I've done this, day 3 and 4 were the worst, although the ways my body has rebelled have varied. This time, I didn't get the migraines that I did the first time I detoxed, but I did have almost constant low-grade dull headaches. On day 4 (Wednesday), I found it almost impossible to focus on anything, felt irritable, restless – it was like I'd drunk a bottle of red cordial neat. I can't imagine what it would be like to have to battle that every single day :S<br /><br />The picture in this post is my tribute to the hot drink that helped me get through the 168 hours of torture: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rooibos">Rooibos</a>. Unlike tea, rooibos is completely caffeine-free, but is still rich in minerals &amp; anti-oxidants. I think it may be in my top 3 hot drinks now (sorry, green tea!), and I expect to be drinking a lot more of it in the future.<br /><br />Okay, now I'm off for a cuppa, see y'all later!<br /><br /><span style="font-style: italic;font-size:85%;" >Photo Creative Commons: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ravissant74/534058328/">wilnora on flickr</a></span></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Caffeine: ultimate love/hate]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/11/caffeine-ultimate-lovehate/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-11T17:27:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/11/caffeine-ultimate-lovehate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_apqCDz1JZos/SeBMCfWf_yI/AAAAAAAAAAU/N5-rFQPDCdI/s1600-h/no-caffeine.jpg"><img style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 200px; height: 150px;" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_apqCDz1JZos/SeBMCfWf_yI/AAAAAAAAAAU/N5-rFQPDCdI/s200/no-caffeine.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5323338365211246370" border="0" /></a><br />Anyone who knows me knows I love my coffee – plunger, espresso, flat white, short macchiato, I'm there. Unfortunately, my love for caffeinated goodness often means my consumption goes up in direct proportion to my busyness levels, until I find myself drinking too much of the stuff.<br /><br />Not being the sort of person that's really capable of doing anything by halves (including coffee drinking), I combat this by going on caffeine fasts, where I'll not drink anything caffeinated for a period of time (usually a week). As I sit here with a nearly-empty thermos of plunger coffee, I can't help but think that it's time for another one.<br /><br />So as of midnight tonight, I'll be completely off caffeine (in any form: tea, coffee, chocolate, energy drinks, whatever) for the entire week. Usually by day 3, my body goes into full-scale rebellion, and tries to make life miserable. Thankfully there aren't any uni classes this week.<br /><br />Wish me luck…<br /><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sugarandweedkiller/1118758309/"><span style="font-size:78%;"><br /><span style="font-style: italic;">Photo Creative Commons: </span></span></a><span class="nickname"><a style="font-style: italic;" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/sugarandweedkiller/1118758309/"><span style="font-size:78%;">GIRLintheCAFE on Flickr</span></a><br /></span></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Stephen McDonald</div>
<div class='content'>
I too am dancing at the door of caffeine's hold. Not one week passes by without a cup of Earl Grey. It's going to take me some time to finish the best price-per-unit purchase of a box of 100 tea bags.<BR/><BR/>Good luck.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
