<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: projects | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/projects/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-10-22T14:59:16+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Curse of the Ideal Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/10/22/the-curse-of-the-ideal-project/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-22T12:25:34+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2014/10/22/the-curse-of-the-ideal-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I confess: I have an ideas problem. Not the <em>generation</em> of ideas, oh no.
My problem is what to <em>do</em> (or <em>not</em> to do) with them when they arrive.</p>

<p>Like many idealistically-bent people, I tend to like the <em>idea</em> more than the <em>implementation</em>. Why is that?</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/andrewdotnich">@andrewdotnich</a> Ideas are perfect. Implementation is chaos.</p>&mdash; Toby Hede (@tobyhede) <a href="https://twitter.com/tobyhede/status/524761857299460097">October 22, 2014</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>And it&rsquo;s true: there is a certain (almost-Platonic) beauty to the Idea. (The idea of idea? #stackoverflow)</p>

<p>You imagine the finished product, and it&rsquo;s wonderful. Oh, to have given birth to such an incredible <em>x</em>!</p>

<p>And then the tarnishing starts. The corrosive factors of<br>
<q>I don&rsquo;t have enough time!</q>, and <br>
<q>I don&rsquo;t know how to do this - maybe I&rsquo;ll fail!</q>, and <br>
<q>oh, someone&rsquo;s already made one of those!</q>, and <br>
<q>oh! I&rsquo;ve just had a great idea for a &hellip;</q></p>

<p>start etching away, and before long the sheen is gone.</p>

<p>Sometimes the tarnish takes longer to take hold than others. A lot of projects might even get started. But it&rsquo;s rare that a project actually makes it to &ldquo;finished&rdquo;,
because the inevitable disappointment when the actual fails to meet the Ideal feels too much to bear.</p>

<p>Wouldn&rsquo;t it be so much nicer, your <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/InsaneTrollLogic">troll-brain says</a>, if things just stayed as ideas? Why not give yourself the reward for coming up with the idea?</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Ko-Ko:</strong> When Your Majesty says &ldquo;Let a thing be done&rdquo;, it’s as good as done, practically it is done, because Your Majesty’s will is law. Your Majesty says &ldquo;Kill a gentleman&rdquo;, and the gentleman is to be killed, consequently that gentleman is as good as dead, practically he is dead, and if he is dead, why not say so?</p>

<p><strong>The Mikado</strong>: I see. <em>(Dramatic Pause)</em> Nothing could possibly be more&hellip;satisfactory!</p>

<p><em>The Mikado</em>, Act II.</p></blockquote>

<p>Only it isn&rsquo;t satisfactory. Eventually, you&rsquo;ll end up with a bunch of baby projects you killed at birth - because
in the moment you decided <q>Not Creating Anything</q> was better than <q>Creating Something Less than Ideal</q>. And we don&rsquo;t live in Plato&rsquo;s universe.
An idea is only a shadow without its fulfilment.</p>

<p>Who wants to live in a world of shadows?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
