<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mcgonagall | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/mcgonagall/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2014-07-03T12:50:53+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: Magistrates, Blegh!]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/07/13/mondays-with-mcgonagall-magistrates_13/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-13T09:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/07/13/mondays-with-mcgonagall-magistrates_13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div>It's been some time since we delved into the priceless treasures contained in W. McGonagall's poetry. Today our protagonist has been banned from performing in the Royal Circus in Dundee, and he is most unimpressed. He is so put out at being treated in such an unfair manner that he's had enough, and is going somewhere he'll be appreciated. Hrumph.</div><div><br /></div><div><br /><hr /><br /><h2>Lines in Protest to the Dundee Magistrates</h2><br /><blockquote><br />Fellow citizens of Bonnie Dundee<br/><img style="float:right; margin:0 0 10px 10px;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 250px; height: 263px;" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_apqCDz1JZos/SlcqhLzCGjI/AAAAAAAAAAs/BOmDg_A0zIs/s400/angry_judge.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5356797031371381298" />Are ye aware how the magistrates have treated me?<br />Nay, do not stare or make a fuss<br />When I tell ye they have boycotted me from appearing in Royal Circus,<br />Which in my opinion is a great shame,<br />And a dishonour to the city's name.<br /><br />Fellow citizens, I consider such treatment to be very hard;<br />'Tis proof for me they have little regard;<br />Or else in the circumstances they would have seen to my protection;<br />Then that would have been a proof of their affection,<br />And how Genius ought to be rewarded,<br />But instead my Genius has been disregarded<br />Why should the magistrates try and punish me in such a cruel form?<br />I never heard the like since I was born.<br />Fellow citizens, they have taken from me a part of my living<br />And as Christians they should have been giving;<br />But instead of that they have prevented Baron Ziegler from engaging me,<br />Which certainly is a disgrace to Bonnie Dundee.<br /><br />Who was't that immortalised the old and the new railway bridges of the Silvery Tay?<br />Also the inauguration of the Hill of Balgay?<br />Likewise the Silvery Tay rolling on its way?<br />And the Newport Railway?<br />Besides the Dundee Volunteers?<br />Which met with their approbation and hearty cheers.<br />And has it come to this in Bonnie Dundee?<br />But, fellow-citizens, I will not submit to such an indignity<br />For I am resolved to leave the city<br />And bid the city a long farewell,<br />For I cannot get protection in it to dwell,<br />Therefore I'm resolved from it to flee<br />For a prophet has no honour in his own country,<br />And try to live in some other town<br />Where the magistrates won't boycott me or try to keep me down<br /><br />No more shall the roughs of Bonnie Dundee<br />Get the chance of insulting or throwing missiles at me<br />For I'm going off to the beautiful west<br />To the fair city of Glasgow that I like the best,<br />Where the River Clyde rolls on to the sea,<br />And the lark and the blackbird whistles with glee.<br />And your beautiful bridges across the River Clyde,<br />And on your bonnie banks I'm going to reside.<br /></blockquote></div></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
hahahaha</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: The Battle of El-Teb]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/25/mondays-with-mcgonagall-battle-of-el/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-25T14:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/25/mondays-with-mcgonagall-battle-of-el</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_UqsRf118B2I/Rsdy9-1rEfI/AAAAAAAAAtk/rLJXr5N3Vec/s400/royal-navy-gatling.jpg"><img style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 216px;" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_UqsRf118B2I/Rsdy9-1rEfI/AAAAAAAAAtk/rLJXr5N3Vec/s400/royal-navy-gatling.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a><br />This week, we're looking at our poet's take on the second <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battles_of_El_Teb">Battle of El-Teb</a>. It doesn't seem to be a particularly important battle on the world stage (particularly for the residents of Dundee, or indeed anywhere), but thanks to his efforts, we can learn about it in a form other than prose...<br /><br /><hr /><br /><h2>The Battle Of El-Teb</h2><br /><blockquote><br /><br />Ye sons of Great Britain, I think no shame<br />To write in praise of brave General Graham!<br />Whose name will be handed down to posterity without any stigma,<br />Because, at the battle of El-Teb, he defeated Osman Digna.<br /><br />With an army about five thousand strong,<br />To El-Teb, in the year 1884, he marched along,<br />And bivouacked there for the night;<br />While around their fires they only thought of the coming fight.<br /><br />They kept up their fires all the long night,<br />Which made the encampment appear weird-like to the sight;<br />While the men were completely soaked with the rain,<br />But the brave heroes disdained to complain.<br /><br />The brave heroes were glad when daylight did appear,<br />And when the reveille was sounded, they gave a hearty cheer<br />And their fires were piled up higher again,<br />Then they tried to dry their clothes that were soaked with the rain.<br /><br />Then breakfast was taken about eight o'clock,<br />And when over, each man stood in the ranks as firm as a rock,<br />And every man seemed to be on his guard --<br />All silent and ready to move forward.<br /><br />The first movement was a short one from where they lay --<br />Then they began to advance towards El-Teb without dismay,<br />And showed that all was in order for the fray,<br />While every man's heart seemed to feel light and gay.<br /><br />The enemy's position could be seen in the distance far away<br />But the brave heroes marched on without delay --<br />Whilst the enemy's banners floated in the air,<br />And dark swarms of men were scattered near by there.<br /><br />Their force was a large one -- its front extended over a mile,<br />And all along the line their guns were all in file;<br />But as the British advanced, they disappeared,<br />While our brave kilty lads loudly cheered.<br /><br />Thus slowly and cautiously brave General Graham proceeded<br />And to save his men from slaughter, great caution was needed,<br />Because Osman Digna's force was about ten thousand strong;<br />But he said, Come on, my brave lads, we'll conquer them ere long!<br /><br />It was about ten o'clock when they came near the enemy's lines,<br />And on the morning air could be heard the cheerful chimes<br />Corning from the pipes of the gallant Black Watch,<br />Which every ear in the British force was eager to catch.<br /><br />Then they passed by the enemy about mid-day,<br />While every Arab seemed to have his gun ready for the fray<br />When a bullet strikes down General Baker by the way,<br />But he is soon in the saddle again without delay,<br /><br />And ready for any service that he could perform;<br />Whilst the bullets fell around them in a perfect storm<br />That they had to lie down, but not through fear,<br />Because the enemy was about 800 yards on their left rear.<br /><br />Then General Graham addressed his men,<br />And said, If they won't attack us, we must attack them,<br />So start to your feet, my lads, and never fear,<br />And strike up your bagpipes, and give a loud cheer.<br /><br />So they leapt to their feet, and gave a loud cheer,<br />While the Arabs swept down upon them without the least fear,<br />And put aside their rifles, and grasped their spears;<br />Whilst the British bullets in front of them the earth uptears.<br /><br />Then the British charged them with their cold steel,<br />Which made the Arabs backward for to reel;<br />But they dashed forward again on their ranks without dismay,<br />But before the terrible fire of their musketry they were swept away.<br /><br />Oh, God of Heaven! it was a terrible sight<br />To see, and hear the Arabs shouting with all their might<br />A fearful oath when they got an inch of cold steel,<br />Which forced them backwards again and made them reel.<br /><br />By two o'clock they were fairly beat,<br />And Osman Digna, the false prophet, was forced to retreat<br />After three hours of an incessant fight;<br />But Heaven, 'tis said, defends the right.<br /><br />And I think he ought to be ashamed of himself;<br />For I consider he has acted the part of a silly elf,<br />By thinking to conquer the armies of the Lord<br />With his foolish and benighted rebel horde.<br /></blockquote></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Lorelei</div>
<div class='content'>
Political correctness aside, this relic is a  jewel in the glorious art of story-tell. Bivouack in peace, McGonagall; what's a fatwa to a dead poet...</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: Autumn]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/18/mondays-with-mcgonagall-autumn/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-18T09:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/18/mondays-with-mcgonagall-autumn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2308/1582876153_9bc7a02fd9.jpg"><img style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 500px; height: 500px;" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2308/1582876153_9bc7a02fd9.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a><br />No explanations this week, just the stanzas...<br /><br /><hr /><br /><h2>Autumn Reverie</h2><br /><blockquote><br />Alas! Beautiful Summer now hath fled,<br />And the face of Nature doth seem dead,<br />And the leaves are withered, and falling off the trees,<br />By the nipping and chilling autumnal breeze.<br /><br />The pleasures of the little birds are all fled,<br />And with the cold many of them will be found dead,<br />Because the leaves of the trees are scattered in the blast,<br />And makes the feathered creatures feel downcast.<br /><br />Because there are no leaves on the trees to shield them from the storm<br />On a windy, and rainy, cloudy morn;<br />Which makes their little hearts throb with pain,<br />By the chilling blast and the pitiless rain.<br /><br />But still they are more contented than the children of God,<br />As long as they can pick up a worm from the sod,<br />Or anything they can get to eat,<br />Just, for instance, a stale crust of bread or a grain of wheat.<br /><br />Oh! Think of the little birds in the time of the snow,<br />Also of the little street waifs, that are driven to and fro,<br />And trembling in the cold blast, and chilled to the bone,<br />For the want of food and clothing, and a warm home.<br /><br />Besides think of the sorrows of the wandering poor,<br />That are wandering in the cold blast from door to door;<br />And begging, for Heaven's sake, a crust of bread,<br />And alas! Not knowing where to lay their head.<br /><br />While the rich are well fed and covered from the cold,<br />While the poor are starving, both young and old;<br />Alas! It is the case in this boasted Christian land,<br />Where as the rich are told to be kind to the poor, is God's command.<br /><br />Oh! Think of the working man when he's no work to do,<br />Who's got a wife and family, perhaps four or two,<br />And the father searching for work, and no work can be had,<br />The thought, I'm sure, 'tis enough to drive the poor man mad.<br /><br />Because for his wife and family he must feel,<br />And perhaps the thought thereof will cause him to steal<br />Bread for his family, that are starving at home,<br />While the thought thereof makes him sigh heavily and groan.<br /><br />Alas! The pangs of hunger are very hard to hide,<br />And few people can their temper control,<br />Or become reconciled to their fate,<br />Especially when they cannot find anything to eat.<br /><br />Oh! Think of the struggles of the poor to make a living,<br />Because the rich unto them seldom are giving;<br />Wereas they are told he that giveth to the poor lendeth unto the Lord,<br />But alas! they rather incline their money to hoard.<br /><br />Then theres the little news-vendors in the street,<br />Running about perhaps with bare feet;<br />And if the rich chance to see such creatures in the street,<br />In general they make a sudden retreat.<br /></blockquote><br /><hr /><span style="font-size:85%;"><br />Photo: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/deniscollette/1582876153/">Denis Collette on Flickr</a>.</span></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Lorelei</div>
<div class='content'>
More than a poet. He's a revolutionary. All pea-throwers owe this man an apology.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: Ode to Edward VII]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/28/mondays-with-mcgonagall-ode-to-edward/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-28T08:38:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/28/mondays-with-mcgonagall-ode-to-edward</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This week's McGonagall (late, I know – I'm sorry) is an ode that William wrote for the coronation of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_VII_of_the_United_Kingdom">Edward VII</a> of England. My guess is he'd been itching to write a coronation poem for years, having spent most of his career during the long reign of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Victoria_of_the_United_Kingdom">Queen Victoria</a>.<br /><hr/><br /><a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/44/Edward_VII_in_coronation_robes.jpg/433px-Edward_VII_in_coronation_robes.jpg"><br/><img style="margin: 60pt 20pt 10px 20px; float: left; cursor: pointer; width: 216px; height: 300px;" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/44/Edward_VII_in_coronation_robes.jpg/433px-Edward_VII_in_coronation_robes.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a><br /><br /><blockquote><br />Oh! God, I thank Thee for restoring King Edward the Seventh's health again,<br />And let all his subjects throughout the Empire say Amen;<br />May God guard him by night and day,<br />At home and abroad, when he's far away.<br /><br />May angels guard his bed at night when he lies down,<br />And may his subjects revere him, and on him do not frown;<br />May he be honoured by them at home and abroad,<br />And may he always be protected by the Eternal God.<br /><br />My blessing on his noble form, and on his lofty head,<br />May all good angels guard him while living and when dead;<br />And when the final hour shall come to summons him away,<br />May his soul be wafted to the realms of bliss I do pray.<br /><br />Long may he reign, happy and serene,<br />Also his Queen most beautiful to be seen;<br />And may God guard his family by night and day,<br />That they may tread in the paths of virtue and not go astray.<br /><br />May God prosper King Edward the Seventh wherever he goes,<br />May he always reign victorious over his foes;<br />Long may he be spared to wear the British Crown,<br />And may God be as a hedge around him at night when he lies down;<br />May God inspire him with wisdom, and long may he reign<br />As Emperor of India and King Edward the VII. --Amen.<br /></blockquote></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Lorelei</div>
<div class='content'>
A half-century of mulling it over pre-coronation seems to have paid off for the poet. The third stanza almost scans, giving this poem a timely and uncharacteristically polished edge.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: Loch Leven]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/20/mondays-with-mcgonagall-loch-leven/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-20T09:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/20/mondays-with-mcgonagall-loch-leven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
More from William's autobiography this week, except this is a poem, with the somewhat hubristic title <i>Magnificent Poem on Loch Leven</i>:<br /><hr/><br /><br /><blockquote style="text-align: center;"><p>Beautiful Loch Leven, near by Kinross,<br />     For a good day's fishing the angler is seldom at a loss,<br />     For the loch it abounds with pike and trout,<br />     Which can be had for the catching without any doubt;<br />     And the scenery around it is most beautiful to be seen,<br />     Especially the Castle, wherein was imprisoned Scotland's ill-starred Queen.</p><p>Then there's the lofty Lomond Hills on the eastern side,<br />     And the loch is long, very deep, very wide;<br />     Then on the southern side there's Benarty's rugged hills,<br />     And from the tops can be seen the village of Kinross with its spinning       mills.</p><p>The big house of Kinross is very handsome to be seen,<br />     With its beautiful grounds around it, and lime trees so green,<br />     And 'tis a magnificent sight to see, on a fine summer afternoon<br />     The bees extracting honey from the leaves when in full bloom.</p>        <p>There the tourist can enjoy himself and while away the hours,<br />     Underneath the lime trees shady bowers,<br />     And listen to the humming of the busy bees,<br />     While they are busy gathering honey from the lime trees.</p>        <p>Then there's the old burying ground near by Kinross,<br />     And the dead that lie there turned into dusty dross,<br />     And the gravestones are all in a state of decay,<br />     And the wall around it is mouldering away.</p></blockquote><br /><br /><script type="text/javascript"><br />var gaJsHost = (("https:" == document.location.protocol) ? "https://ssl." : "http://www.");<br />document.write(unescape("%3Cscript src='" + gaJsHost + "google-analytics.com/ga.js' type='text/javascript'%3E%3C/script%3E"));<br /></script><br /><script type="text/javascript"><br />try {<br />var pageTracker = _gat._getTracker("UA-8444077-1");<br />pageTracker._trackPageview();<br />} catch(err) {}</script></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Lorelei</div>
<div class='content'>
Whether it's trains, queens or lochs, he succeeds in ending his poems with a death theme. Macabre achievements aside, he is right of course about the scenery. It deserves a magnificent poem. Bring it on.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
What do you expect? The guy's a poet, not a botanist! :D</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Stephen McDonald</div>
<div class='content'>
Mr McGonagall's understanding of pollination is interesting: "The bees extracting honey from the LEAVES when in full bloom."</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
