<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gfc | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/gfc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2016-10-18T16:33:31+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: Autumn]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/18/mondays-with-mcgonagall-autumn/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-18T09:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/05/18/mondays-with-mcgonagall-autumn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}" href="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2308/1582876153_9bc7a02fd9.jpg"><img style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 500px; height: 500px;" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2308/1582876153_9bc7a02fd9.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></a><br />No explanations this week, just the stanzas...<br /><br /><hr /><br /><h2>Autumn Reverie</h2><br /><blockquote><br />Alas! Beautiful Summer now hath fled,<br />And the face of Nature doth seem dead,<br />And the leaves are withered, and falling off the trees,<br />By the nipping and chilling autumnal breeze.<br /><br />The pleasures of the little birds are all fled,<br />And with the cold many of them will be found dead,<br />Because the leaves of the trees are scattered in the blast,<br />And makes the feathered creatures feel downcast.<br /><br />Because there are no leaves on the trees to shield them from the storm<br />On a windy, and rainy, cloudy morn;<br />Which makes their little hearts throb with pain,<br />By the chilling blast and the pitiless rain.<br /><br />But still they are more contented than the children of God,<br />As long as they can pick up a worm from the sod,<br />Or anything they can get to eat,<br />Just, for instance, a stale crust of bread or a grain of wheat.<br /><br />Oh! Think of the little birds in the time of the snow,<br />Also of the little street waifs, that are driven to and fro,<br />And trembling in the cold blast, and chilled to the bone,<br />For the want of food and clothing, and a warm home.<br /><br />Besides think of the sorrows of the wandering poor,<br />That are wandering in the cold blast from door to door;<br />And begging, for Heaven's sake, a crust of bread,<br />And alas! Not knowing where to lay their head.<br /><br />While the rich are well fed and covered from the cold,<br />While the poor are starving, both young and old;<br />Alas! It is the case in this boasted Christian land,<br />Where as the rich are told to be kind to the poor, is God's command.<br /><br />Oh! Think of the working man when he's no work to do,<br />Who's got a wife and family, perhaps four or two,<br />And the father searching for work, and no work can be had,<br />The thought, I'm sure, 'tis enough to drive the poor man mad.<br /><br />Because for his wife and family he must feel,<br />And perhaps the thought thereof will cause him to steal<br />Bread for his family, that are starving at home,<br />While the thought thereof makes him sigh heavily and groan.<br /><br />Alas! The pangs of hunger are very hard to hide,<br />And few people can their temper control,<br />Or become reconciled to their fate,<br />Especially when they cannot find anything to eat.<br /><br />Oh! Think of the struggles of the poor to make a living,<br />Because the rich unto them seldom are giving;<br />Wereas they are told he that giveth to the poor lendeth unto the Lord,<br />But alas! they rather incline their money to hoard.<br /><br />Then theres the little news-vendors in the street,<br />Running about perhaps with bare feet;<br />And if the rich chance to see such creatures in the street,<br />In general they make a sudden retreat.<br /></blockquote><br /><hr /><span style="font-size:85%;"><br />Photo: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/deniscollette/1582876153/">Denis Collette on Flickr</a>.</span></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Lorelei</div>
<div class='content'>
More than a poet. He's a revolutionary. All pea-throwers owe this man an apology.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
