<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: vegetables | andrewdotnich]]></title>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/categories/vegetables/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//"/>
  <updated>2013-02-05T10:56:10+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Nicholson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sorry, I was miles away…]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-11T00:54:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2011/08/11/redeeming-some-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote>"Blinded by distractions,<br />lost in matter-less affairs…"<br />&mdash; dc Talk, "Day By Day"<br /></blockquote><br />Recently while sitting on a train, a largely unremarkable thing happened &ndash; so unremarkable it gave me pause for thought. What was this non-event? <br /><br />I got a new PB in Bejeweled Blitz. Not just any Personal Best: I cracked the half-million mark (and beat my previous best by over 150,000)! I enjoyed the quick squirt of adrenaline as it shot through my body, and then I thought: "Huh."<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s1600/1png.png" imageanchor="1" style="clear:right; float:right; margin-left:1em; margin-bottom:1em"><img border="0" height="400" width="267" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-sNOrDQVPYy4/TkKSmBRrWAI/AAAAAAAAADc/vNWa-NNRMN0/s400/1png.png" /></a></div><br />For a while now I've become increasingly frustrated and annoyed at the way the Internet and smart phones have trained my attention patterns &mdash; the classic Gen-Y dance I call "The Context-Switch One-Step". Take your electronic distraction generator in one hand, drop your head slightly, place earphones in ears, and away we go, with a one-two-three, one-two-three, facebook-check, twitter-feeds, email-check, one-more-game, when's-that-tram, one-two-three&hellip;<br /><br />&hellip;sorry.<br /><br />Such constant "engagement" (from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skinner_boxes">pellet-popping</a> to <a href="http://drinking-from-the-firehose.urbanup.com/1867465">drinking from the firehose</a>) has made it very hard for my brain to either 1) switch off or 2) give undivided attention to just one thing. Sometimes this is a benefit, but mostly, it just leaves me distracted and not at rest.<br /><br />This spills out into all sorts of areas; why bother taking the time to cook a healthy meal when "fast food" slips into the cycle more easily? Or <a href="http://www.harmonicalessons.com/">learning a new skill</a>? Or making any time investment at all?<br /><br />But the place where rubber hits road for me the hardest is spending time with God &mdash; how can <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-1.html">I</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/04/voice-part-2.html">be</a> <a href="http://andrewdotnich.blogspot.com/2011/06/voice-part-3.html">still</a> when everything in my mind screams "hurry, hurry, faster, more!" How can I spend time meditating on a chunk of connected verses, when they seem to meld into a stream of 140-character morsels right before my eyes?<br /><br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_New_World">Aldous Huxley would be horrified&hellip;</a></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Andy</div>
<div class='content'>
Arthur: I love that picture - every time I come across it it hits home with new force, and it&#39;s a both/and scenario here in the West!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Arthur</div>
<div class='content'>
Or maybe Huxley would just <a href="http://www.acceleratingfuture.com/michael/blog/images/Amusing-Ourselves-To-Death.jpg" rel="nofollow">smile knowingly</a>...<br /><br />I love your description of the one-step!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Rebecca Simon</div>
<div class='content'>
Oh wow, this totally hit home with me. I can so relate! Being a Gen-Y tech/facebook junky frustrates me no end. The days of concentrating seem to have disappeared....but I&#39;m determined to rediscover them somehow.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mondays with McGonagall: Peas]]></title>
    <link href="http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/13/mondays-with-mcgonagall-peas/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-13T08:30:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://andrewdotni.ch//blog/2009/04/13/mondays-with-mcgonagall-peas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This week's Monday with McGonagall comes from his autobiographical writings, and explains his first performance-related encounter with peas…<br /><br /><hr /><br /><blockquote><br /><p><br />My Dearly Beloved Readers, – I will begin with giving an account of my experiences amongst the publicans. Well, I must say that the first man who threw peas at me was a publican, while I was giving an entertainment to a few of my admirers in a public-house in a certain little village not far from Dundee but, my dear friends, I wish it to be understood that the publican who threw the peas at me was not the     landlord of the public-house, he was one of the party who came to hear me give my entertainment.<br /></p><p>Well, my dear readers, it was while I was singing my own song, <i>The Rattling Boy from Dublin Town</i>, that he threw the peas at me. You must understand that the Rattling Boy was courting a lass called Biddy Brown, and the Rattling Boy chanced to meet his Biddy one night in company with another lad called Barney Magee, which, of course, he did not like to see, and he told Biddy he considered it too bad for her to be going about with another lad, and he would bid her good-bye for being untrue to him. Then Barney Magee told the Rattling Boy that Biddy Brown was his lass, and that he could easily find another – and come and have a glass, and be friends. </p><p>But the Rattling Boy told Barney Magee to give his glass of strong drink to the devil! meaning, I suppose, it was only fit for devils to make use of, not for God's creatures. Because, my friends, too often has strong drink been the cause of seducing many a beautiful young woman away from her true lover, and from her parents also, by a false seducer which, no doubt, the Rattling Boy considered Barney Magee to be.</p><p> Therefore, my dear friends, the reason, I think, for the publican throwing the peas at me is because I say, to the devil with your glass, in my song, <i>The Rattling Boy from Dublin</i>, and he, no doubt, considered it had a teetotal tendency about it, and, for that reason, he had felt angry, and had thrown the peas at me.</p></blockquote></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Lorelei</div>
<div class='content'>
A Rattling Boy? So he makes a sound like a rattle? No wonder Biddy hit the bottle.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
